So today, we're very pleased to have as our second, um,
所以今天，我们很高兴有第二个，嗯，
invited speaker, Richard Socher,
特邀发言人Richard Socher，
he is the chief scientist at Salesforce.
他是Salesforce的首席科学家。
Um, Richard actually also has a lot more connection to this class,
嗯，理查德实际上也和这个班级有很多联系，
um, because, um, for several years, um,
嗯，因为，嗯，好几年了，嗯，
Richard was involved either as instructor or, um,
理查德既是教练，也是嗯，
co-instructor in teaching this material at Stanford,
在斯坦福大学教授这些材料的共同指导
um, so he sort of knows the course, um, pretty well.
嗯，所以他有点了解课程，嗯，非常好。
Um, and so today,
嗯，今天，
he's going to be talking about some of the challenges and recent work
他将谈论一些挑战和最近的工作
in doing multitask learning in natural language processing. So welcome, Richard.
在自然语言处理中进行多任务学习。理查德，欢迎你。
Thank you. Hello, everybody. I'm excited to be here.
谢谢。大家好。我很高兴能来到这里。
Uh, yeah, I want to talk to you today about what we,
呃，是的，我想今天和你谈谈我们是什么，
in short, called decaNLP.
简而言之，称为decaNLP。
I want to first give a big shout out to Bryan McCann.
我想首先向Bryan McCann大声喊叫。
He's the first author of this, uh, paper,
他是第一个作者，呃，纸，
and I've pitched this idea to a lot of people in the last, like,
我把这个想法推到了最后的很多人，比如，
three to four years,
三到四年，
and most people were like,
大多数人都喜欢，
"This is too much pre-processing because you're trying to
“这是太多的预处理，因为你正在尝试
do 10 different tasks in one model."
在一个模型中完成10个不同的任务。“
That's sort of where the decathlon, uh,
那就是十项全能比赛，呃，
wording comes in, uh, but he,
措辞进来了，呃，但他，
he really stuck to it, uh,
他真的坚持了，呃，
did all the pre-processing and all the things that you now know like tokenization,
做了所有预处理和你现在知道的所有事情，如标记化，
and it turns out a lot of different data sets,
结果证明了很多不同的数据集，
have a different conception of what a word is.
对一个词的含义有不同的概念。
This wasn't two words,
这不是两个字，
uh, or one word,
呃，或者一个字，
and things like that, and that changes how you
和那样的事情，这会改变你的方式
write all your evaluation scripts and all of that.
写下你所有的评估脚本和所有这些。
So Bryan, uh, is,
所以布莱恩，恩，是，
is a really phenomenal researcher,
是一位真正非凡的研究员，
uh, with us in the group,
呃，和我们在一起，
and Nitish has helped us a lot on the optimization side of this,
而Nitish在优化方面为我们提供了很多帮助，
uh, and then Caiming Xiong,
呃，然后是Caiming Xiong，
the Director of Research, has done a lot of, uh,
研究总监做了很多，呃，
really phenomenal work that's kind of helpful in pretty much all our projects.
非常惊人的工作，对我们所有的项目都很有帮助。
So I'm going to tell you a couple of different, uh,
所以我要告诉你几个不同的，呃，
lines of reasoning that led us to,
引导我们的推理线，
uh, this idea of multitask learning.
呃，这个多任务学习的想法。
And the first one was sort of trying to take a step back and looking at the field,
第一个是试图退后一步，看着田野，
and I noticed not like that much of a historical class but basically pre-2010,
我注意到不像历史课那么多，但基本上在2010年之前，
most natural language processing had kind of these very hand-designed features,
大多数自然语言处理都有这些非常手工设计的功能，
and we basically just had,
而我们基本上只是，
uh, machine learning kind of learned weights,
呃，机器学习一种学到的重量，
uh, in the optimization procedure for these human-designed features.
呃，在这些人为设计的功能的优化过程中。
And so in 2010, Chris and I and others sort of started to work in deep learning for feature learning.
所以在2010年，克里斯和我和其他人开始从事深度学习功能学习。
So everything was a word vector and now,
所以一切都是单词矢量，现在，
we can back-propagate into them and actually learn those representations.
我们可以反向传播到它们中并实际学习这些表示。
And I think currently,
我想现在，
we're kind of in a state where we do a lot of
我们处在一个我们做很多事情的州
deep architecture engineering for specific tasks,
针对特定任务的深层架构工程，
and you've seen this already.
你已经看过了。
You have like an NER model,
你喜欢NER模型，
you have a question and answering model,
你有问题和回答模型，
you have a translation model,
你有翻译模型，
and we basically now,
我们基本上现在，
each of these communities has at least, uh,
这些社区中的每一个都至少有，呃，
converged on is probably some kind of neural network,
融合可能是某种神经网络，
but there's still a lot of different kinds of architectures of
但是仍然有很多不同类型的架构
these neural networks that you're working on for each different task.
这些神经网络，你正在为每个不同的任务工作。
And so the question is like, okay,
所以问题就像，好吧，
we're gonna probably do that for
我们可能会这样做
another couple of years because we're making good progress,
再过几年，因为我们取得了良好的进展，
but what's sort of next,
但是下一步是什么
uh, on the research side?
呃，在研究方面？
And what I actually love about this class so much is that
我真正喜欢这堂课的是那个
you go from like maybe not knowing much about NLP at
你可能不会对NLP了解太多
all to you can basically understand
一切都可以基本了解
the state-of-the-art research papers as they come out now,
他们现在出来的最先进的研究论文，
uh, and this, this is one of those.
呃，这就是其中之一。
Uh, so [NOISE] why,
呃，所以[NOISE]为什么，
why not continue to work in this multitask regime?
为什么不继续在这个多任务机制中工作？
In some ways, I feel like, uh,
在某些方面，我觉得，呃，
the community is a little bit, uh,
社区有点，呃，
like this cute dog, where we, kind of,
像这只可爱的狗，我们在哪里，有点像，
randomly restart, uh, after every project.
在每个项目之后随机重启，呃。
And it's kind of clear to me that if you have a lot of training data, uh,
我很清楚，如果你有很多训练数据，呃，
and you define a specific data set and task on that data set,
并在该数据集上定义特定的数据集和任务，
you start to architecture engineer in your model to hill-climb on a particular metric,
你开始在你的模型中使用建筑工程师来攀爬特定的度量标准，
or leaderboard, or publications,
或排行榜或出版物，
or products, or whatever it is, uh,
或产品，或其他任何东西，呃，
then as long as your data set has
只要你的数据集有
roughly a good representative set of
大致是一个很好的代表性组合
1,000 times the number of output classes that you have,
您拥有的输出类数量的1,000倍，
you'll probably get it into a regi- regime where you're in the 80 to 90 percent accuracy,
你可能会把它变成一个准确率高达80％到90％的区域，
or if one, where you're basically doing pretty okay.
或者如果一个，你基本上做得很好。
And of course, now when you look at trends on ImageNet,
当然，现在当你看看ImageNet的趋势时，
you have 1,000 different classes in computer vision,
你有1000个不同的计算机视觉课程，
1,000 different classes, each has 1,000 images.
1,000个不同的类，每个类有1,000个图像。
So if you have roughly a million images, you do pretty well.
因此，如果您有大约一百万张图像，那么您可以做得非常好。
And in machine translation, ideally,
在机器翻译中，理想情况下，
you know, I have many more, I have like hundreds of thousands of words,
你知道，我还有更多，我有几十万字，
so you want many millions of examples of each of the word in their,
所以你想要他们的每个单词的数百万个例子，
uh, words in their context.
呃，在他们的背景下的话。
And of course, you know, that the caveat is
当然，你知道，这个警告是
machine translation doesn't work to the level of humans,
机器翻译不适用于人类，
but it works well enough to have it at least in products,
但它至少在产品中运行良好，
and even the best human translators use it as sort of a pre-translation and then,
甚至最优秀的人工翻译也会将其用作预翻译，然后，
uh, sort of, clean it up.
呃，有点，清理它。
And so it's also clear to me that in this regime,
所以我也很清楚，在这个政权中，
and if we want to get to, sort of,
如果我们想要，有点，
more general AI features, uh,
更一般的AI功能，呃，
we need to have some kind of more continuous learning of a single model.
我们需要对单一模型进行某种更持续的学习。
Because if we keep restarting at every project,
因为如果我们在每个项目中继续重启，
we're never going to get to a single model that, kind of,
我们永远不会得到一个单一的模型，那种，
encompasses more and more of the complexity of natural language.
包含越来越多的自然语言的复杂性。
And, uh, when I say we start from random,
而且，呃，当我说我们从随机开始时，
you of course know that that's not quite true
你当然知道那不是真的
because we do have some things that we pre-train,
因为我们确实有一些我们预训练的东西，
namely word vectors, and in computer vision,
即词向量，在计算机视觉中，
we have even more things.
我们还有更多的东西。
And so in some ways that is, ah,
所以在某些方面，啊，
an aspiring ideal for NLP,
一个有抱负的NLP理想，
because in computer vision, you would be, kind of,
因为在计算机视觉中，你会是那样的，
crazy to not use some kind of
疯狂不使用某种
convolution neural network that has pre-train- has been pre-trained on some kind of
具有预训练的卷积神经网络已经在某种类型上进行了预训练
tasks like ImageNet when you start with your project and
当你从项目开始时，像ImageNet这样的任务
try to classify objects or do object detection and a lot of other things.
尝试对对象进行分类或进行对象检测以及许多其他事情。
And in some ways that the whole community could get behind it very quickly,
在某些方面，整个社区可以很快得到支持，
because I mean, you know, once it worked, uh,
因为我的意思是，你知道，一旦它奏效了，呃，
reasonably well, because there was a, sort of,
相当好，因为有一种，有点，
single blocking task in computer vision.
计算机视觉中的单一阻塞任务。
If you can't even tell apart a dog from a cat from a house,
如果你甚至不能把狗从房子里分开来，
it doesn't really make sense to think of even larger, uh, vision projects.
想到更大的呃视觉项目真的没有意义。
And in NLP, we've had a lot of success with word vectors,
在NLP中，我们在单词向量方面取得了很大的成功，
you know a lot of those now,
你现在知道很多
and it started for, sort of, just a small, uh,
它开始了，只是一个小的，呃，
window-based approach or Word2Vec and GloVe, uh,
基于窗口的方法或Word2Vec和GloVe，呃，
then we had, uh, context vectors that were trained, uh,
然后我们有，呃，训练过的上下文向量，呃，
on machine translation, but basically,
机器翻译，但基本上，
instead of just having a single set of words,
而不是只有一组单词，
we actually pre-trained some of the NLSTMs that came on top of those word vectors,
我们实际上预先训练了一些基于这些单词向量的NLSTM，
and, uh, the way we train that, uh,
而且，呃，我们训练的方式，呃，
was also actually Bryan McCann's paper on
实际上也是布莱恩麦肯的论文
contextual vectors with machine translation and then ELMo,
带有机器翻译的上下文向量，然后是ELMo，
kind of, replaced machine translation with, uh, language modeling,
用呃，语言建模取代机器翻译，
which of course is even better because there's even more training data,
这当然更好，因为还有更多的训练数据，
and it still tells you a lot, uh,
它仍然告诉你很多，呃，
and kind of captures in some ways a more complex version of
并且在某些方面捕获更复杂的版本
distributional sort of hypotheses that we had in simpler word vectors,
我们在更简单的单词向量中的分布式假设，
and BERT, not quite a language model but also, kind of,
和BERT，不是一个语言模型，但也有点，
trying to predict words in their context, uh,
试图在他们的背景下预测单词，呃，
but pre-training a lot more layers and a lot deeper networks.
但是预先培训了更多层次和更深层次的网络。
And so we see the success of pre-training a certain set of weights.
因此，我们看到预训练一组权重的成功。
And so the question is,
所以问题是，
why not try to pre-train the entire model?
为什么不尝试预先培训整个模型？
As in including your output,
在包括你的输出，
your softmax, your pointer mechanisms and everything,
你的softmax，你的指针机制和一切，
and then just taking a completely pre-trained model and trying to do something,
然后只需要一个完全预先训练好的模型并尝试做某事，
and that is, kind of, the goal that we have.
那就是我们的目标。
And so, uh, we, sort of,
所以，呃，我们，有点像，
ask ourselves why hasn't this happened?
问问自己为什么不发生这种情况？
Why are we, you know,
你知道，为什么我们
the first to think about, like,
第一个想到的，比如，
trying to pre-train the entirety of the model,
试图预先训练整个模型，
the encoders, and decoders,
编码器和解码器，
and outputs, and everything.
和输出，以及一切。
Uh, and I think part of it is that NLP requires a lot of different kinds of reasoning.
呃，我认为部分原因是NLP需要很多不同的推理。
You've seen many of them already.
你已经看过很多了。
You have some logical reasoning like 550 people in this room,
你有一些逻辑推理，像这个房间里的550人，
25 leave, are there still people in the room,
25日离开，房间里还有人，
and you logically can answer that question,
你在逻辑上可以回答这个问题，
and you have lots of different kinds of linguistic and emotional reasoning,
你有很多不同类型的语言和情感推理，
sentiment analysis, you know,
情绪分析，你知道，
this is a typical Nicolas Cage movie and then you need to know that that's a
这是典型的尼古拉斯凯奇电影，然后你需要知道这是一个
probably negative review unless you like Nicolas Cage movies.
除非你喜欢Nicolas Cage的电影，否则可能会出现负面评论。
Um, no judgment. And, uh,
嗯，没有判断力。而且，呃，
you know, visual types of reasoning and so on.
你知道，视觉类型的推理等等。
And so I think partly because of that complexity in the beginning to feel,
所以我认为部分是因为开始时的复杂感，
didn't really make much progress and now and then kind of separate it.
并没有真正取得太大进展，现在又有点分开了。
And I think in some cases, kind of artificially separated into all these separate tasks,
我认为在某些情况下，人为地分成所有这些单独的任务，
like you have named entity recognition,
就像你已经命名实体识别，
part of speech tagging, and semantic role labeling and, and so on.
词性标注，语义角色标注等等。
And, and in some ways- and it sounds kind of snarky but,
并且，在某些方面 - 听起来有些讽刺，但是，
you know, it made a lot of sense at the time,
你知道，它在当时很有意义，
and it allowed us to make a lot of progress in the community,
它让我们在社区上取得了很大的进步，
but basically we started chasing these benchmarks,
但基本上我们开始追逐这些基准，
and all these different communities, kind of,
以及所有这些不同的社区，
started going off in their own ways.
开始以自己的方式走了。
And we even have some communities that say,
我们甚至有一些社区说，
"We do general question answering,
“我们做一般问题回答，
and there's literally workshops on general question answering, and when I asked,
这里有关于一般问答的研讨会，当我问到时，
uh, the organizers, "Can I ask your model what the sentiment is of this tweet?"
呃，组织者，“我可以问你的模特这条推文的情绪是什么吗？”
They're like, "No, that's sentiment analysis. Go to that different workshop.
他们就像是，“不，那是情感分析。去那个不同的工作室。
It's down, down the hall."
它在大厅下面。“
But I'm like, "That's a- that's a question.
但我想，“那是一个 - 这是一个问题。
Why can't you answer it in the general question answering workshop?"
为什么你不能在一般的问答工作坊里回答呢？“
Um, and so a lot of people then say,
嗯，所以很多人说，
"Well, if you want to work on more general stuff,
“好吧，如果你想做更多的一般事情，
it has to be an unsupervised, kind of,
它必须是无人监督的，
task and the, the feature will not be supervised."
任务和，该功能将不受监督。“
I don't think NLP will be completely unsupervised,
我认为NLP不会完全无人监督，
and we won't solve it, uh, completely unsupervised,
我们不会解决它，呃，完全无人监督，
because in the end, language has a lot of supervision for people,
因为最后语言对人有很多监督，
uh, and, uh, I think for, for systems also.
呃，我想，对于系统来说也是如此。
Uh, and you won't, you know,
呃，你不会，你知道，
if you have- there's a child and it's in a jungle,
如果你有一个孩子，它在丛林中，
it will probably develop a pretty good visual cortex by itself,
它本身可能会形成一个非常好的视觉皮层，
but it won't develop language by itself.
但它本身不会发展语言。
And then- and then also, like,
然后 - 然后也像，
I think if you'll just allow AI's to talk to one another,
我想如果你只是允许AI与对方交谈，
it makes very little sense for them to try to come up with as
对他们来说，尝试提出这个问题毫无意义
inefficient of a communication protocol as humans have with, you know,
你知道，人类所拥有的通信协议效率低下
sequential processing of language because algorithms and computers could,
因为算法和计算机可以顺序处理语言，
if there's no supervision of human language,
如果没有人类语言的监督，
they could just communicate in much more efficient ways with one another.
他们可以以更有效的方式彼此沟通。
So I think it's fairly clear,
所以我觉得很清楚，
we need a lot of supervision, uh, in NLP.
在NLP，我们需要很多监督。
And so basically, all of this has led us, uh,
基本上，所有这些都导致了我们，呃，
to trying to think about a unified multitask model for a lot of different NLP tasks.
尝试为许多不同的NLP任务考虑统一的多任务模型。
By the way, if you have any questions, just raise your hand.
顺便说一句，如果您有任何疑问，请举手。
Okay, let's make this very interactive.
好吧，让我们把它变得非常互动。
Um, basically, we want this unified model, uh,
嗯，基本上，我们想要这个统一的模型，呃，
to decide how to transfer knowledge,
决定如何转移知识，
uh, and not have it, sort of, be manually assigned.
呃，没有，有点，手动分配。
Like in most cases,
像在大多数情况下一样
when you assign your project you say, "Oh,
当你分配你的项目时，你说：“哦，
well I know that named entity recognition part of speech tagging help each other.
我知道命名实体识别部分语音标记相互帮助。
Because once you know something is a noun,
因为一旦你知道什么是名词，
then it's more likely that it's also a named entity."
那么它更可能也是一个命名实体。“
And in this case, we want to basically allow for the single unified model
在这种情况下，我们希望基本上允许单一的统一模型
to know itself how to do domain adaptation and wha- how to share the weights,
了解自己如何进行域适应，以及如何分享权重，
and that will hopefully then lead to a lot of,
这将有希望导致很多，
uh, transfer learning and zero shot learning capabilities.
呃，转移学习和零射击学习能力。
I also think that if we get to this, sort of,
我也认为如果我们达到这个目的，
hard goal of having a single fa- single unified multitask model,
拥有单一统一的多任务模型的艰难目标，
then we'll easy-  be able to more easily adapt it to
那么我们将很容易 - 能够更容易地适应它
new tasks and we'll be also able to deploy it in production more quickly.
新任务，我们也能够更快地在生产中部署它。
If nowadays you want to build
如果你现在想要建立
a little squirrel detector and connect it to your sprinkler system,
一个小松鼠探测器并将其连接到您的喷水灭火系统，
you can just download some off-the-shelf software,
你可以下载一些现成的软件，
and it will basically, kind of, work.
它基本上会有点工作。
That is not the case if you try to do
如果你试图这样做，情况并非如此
a pretty complex language project where you
你是一个非常复杂的语言项目
want to translate into some completely new language or,
想翻译成一些全新的语言或者，
you know, analyze some website and then do something else afterwards.
你知道，分析一些网站，然后再做一些其他事情。
So, uh, you also,
所以，呃，你也是，
when you actually try to deploy and use these kinds of tools and companies,
当你真正尝试部署和使用这些工具和公司时，
you'll realize that there are a lot of different kinds of groups.
你会发现有很多种不同的群体。
There's the search group,
有搜索组，
and the chatbot team,
和聊天机器人团队，
and the translation team,
和翻译团队，
and, uh, and the social sentiment analysis team,
而且，呃，社交情绪分析团队，
and they all use different models,
他们都使用不同的模型，
and they all deploy different models,
他们都部署了不同的模型，
and they all have to build a lot of overhead into
他们都必须建立大量的开销
the core of the- or around that core of an AI model.
人工智能模型的核心 - 或围绕其核心。
So basically, um, lastly,
所以基本上，嗯，最后，
it was, sort of, what we had with, with this dog.
有点像我们用这只狗一样的东西。
I think that once we have this unified model,
我想一旦我们拥有这个统一的模型，
it will also be a first step to being able to
这也是能够迈出的第一步
then continually learn this and just have a single model that just
然后不断学习这个，只有一个模型
gets better and better over time and starts
随着时间的推移变得越来越好
to capture more and more of the complexity of language.
捕捉越来越多的语言复杂性。
All right, any questions around, sort of,
好的，任何问题，有点，
the motivation high level?
动机高水平？
All right. So then, uh,
行。那么，呃，
it's sort of the question, how do we actually make that happen?
这是一个问题，我们如何实际实现这一目标？
And then we -- I first sort of sat down and looked at, like,
然后我们 - 我第一次坐下来看着，就像，
the general sort of formats of all the tasks that you may experience in
您可能遇到的所有任务的一般格式
this class and that NLP sort of has as a field in
这个类和那个NLP类似于一个字段
general and I think they can broadly classified,
一般而且我认为它们可以大致分类，
be classified into these three different categories.
分为这三个不同的类别。
Sequence tagging, you already know.
序列标记，你已经知道了。
Things like NER or aspect-specific sentiment or in
像NER或特定方面的情绪或在
a specific context we want to classify if a word is positive or negative.
如果一个词是正面的还是负面的，我们想要分类的特定背景。
Uh, and then text classification,
呃，然后文字分类，
just a single label for the entire piece of text
只是整个文本的一个标签
and then sequence the sequence a lot of different, you know,
然后对序列进行排序很多不同，你知道，
problems fall into that and I actually personally love, uh,
问题属于那个，我个人真的爱，呃，
these three particular tasks: machine translation, summarization, question answering.
这三个特殊任务：机器翻译，摘要，问答。
Because they are immediately useful that you don't have to explain to somebody,
因为它们是立即有用的，你不必向某人解释，
"Oh, but why do you need the semantic role labeller or parser? "
“哦，但你为什么需要语义角色贴标机或解析器呢？”
If you're a layman and you, you know,
如果你是一个外行而你，你知道，
on the Internet you understand immediately why it's
在互联网上，你立即明白为什么会这样
useful to do summarization, question answering,
有用的做摘要，问答，
or translation and an improvement in
或翻译和改进
those tasks kind of immediately translates in- into better products,
那些任务可以立即转化为更好的产品，
uh, and people being able to communicate better and more efficiently with language.
呃，人们能够用语言更好，更有效地沟通。
So, that, uh, kind of analysis led us to think,
所以，呃，那种分析让我们思考，
uh, about these what I call three equivalent supertasks of NLP.
呃，关于这些我称之为NLP的三个等价超级算法。
Uh, and basically they are
呃，基本上他们是
language modeling, question answer now- question answering and dialogue systems.
语言建模，现在问题答案 - 问题回答和对话系统。
Uh, language modeling, basically trying to predin- predict the next word,
呃，语言建模，基本上试图预测下一个词，
you've already worked on that.
你已经做过那个了。
Uh, and usually it's only used to rescore or basically to pre-train these days.
呃，通常它只用于重新训练或基本上用于训练这些天。
But really if you ask me a question and then you try to predict the next couple of words,
但是，如果你问我一个问题，然后你试着预测接下来的几个字，
then that is also language modeling
那也是语言建模
and if you're able to predict the next couple of words after a question, like,
如果你能够在一个问题之后预测下几个单词，比如
what were the named entities in the sentence and then you just generate, you know,
在句子中命名的实体是什么，然后你只是生成，你知道，
Dresden was a location,
德累斯顿是一个位置，
Richard was a person and whatnot.
理查德是个人而不是。
Uh, then you can kind of cast almost all of these tasks into language modeling.
呃，那么你可以将几乎所有这些任务都投入到语言建模中。
Uh, similarly question answering,
呃，同样问题回答，
you can ask any kind of question,
你可以问任何问题，
what is the translation,
什么是翻译，
what's the summary, uh, and so on,
什么是摘要，呃，等等，
and then with dialogue right now it's kind of tricky because there are
然后现在进行对话有点棘手，因为有
no really good dialogue datasets out there and a lot of times you want some interaction,
没有真正好的对话数据集，很多时候你想要一些互动，
you have to run user studies and most of the existing NLP task would
你必须运行用户研究和大多数现有的NLP任务
basically be pretty short one-step dialogues like what are the named entity tags,
基本上是很短的一步对话，比如什么是命名的实体标签，
and you give them and that's it.
你给他们，就是这样。
So it's a little bit overkill and because of that we basically converged,
所以它有点矫枉过正，因为我们基本上融合了，
uh, on question answering as our main formalism.
呃，问题回答是我们的主要形式主义。
And here is now an overview of the 10 different tasks that we have,
现在，我们概述了我们拥有的10项不同任务，
uh, and we cast all of them as question answering.
呃，我们把所有这些作为问题回答。
These are literally the tr- the training,
这些实际上是训练，
uh, the format of the training dataset, uh,
呃，训练数据集的格式，呃，
and eventually also the way we formulate
最终也是我们制定的方式
the test set and you'll see basically for every single task,
测试集，你会看到基本上每一项任务，
you have a context as some kind of document.
你有一个上下文作为某种文档。
It could be a Wikipedia article,
它可能是维基百科的文章，
it could be a tweet, it could be a longer document,
它可能是一条推文，它可能是一个更长的文件，
whatever, and you ask a question about it and you want to generate an answer.
无论如何，你问一个关于它的问题，你想要产生一个答案。
And I'm actually -- I'm curious if you can think of any task in NLP
我实际上 - 如果你能想到NLP中的任何任务，我很好奇
that couldn't be formulated in this kind of structure.
这种结构无法制定。
Uh, so, let's go over some of these.
呃，那么，让我们来看看其中的一些。
Uh, the first one is sort of the standard,
呃，第一个是标准的，
uh, task that all- you're all familiar with now.
呃，任务你们现在都熟悉了。
The SQuAD, Stanford Question Answering Dataset.
SQUAD，斯坦福问题答疑数据集。
Uh, where the answer is essentially a phrase somewhere in the context.
呃，答案基本上是上下文中的一个短语。
But then, uh, the second one is something that you would never see in most,
但是，呃，第二个是大多数人都看不到的东西，
uh, generalized, uh, question answering workshops and that is, uh,
呃，概括的，呃，问答工作坊，也就是说，呃，
having a context of the single sentence asking what is the translation from
有一个单句的上下文询问是什么翻译
English into German and the output is again a sequence of words but in this case,
英语到德语，输出又是一系列单词，但在这种情况下，
and we color them differently here.
我们在这里为它们着色不同
Uh, this is blue because all these words are basically not in the context and not in
呃，这是蓝色的，因为所有这些词基本上都不在上下文中而不在
the question and we will just generate them
问题，我们将生成它们
with a standard softmax to basically answer this question.
用标准的softmax来基本回答这个问题。
We can also ask what is the summary and you can see that those
我们也可以问一下摘要是什么，你可以看到那些
two in some ways is artificial to make them into a natural language question.
在某些方面，两个是人为的，使它们成为一个自然语言问题。
You could just say translate or summarize and this is just like
你可以说翻译或总结，这就像
one kind of task token in your network but actually half of these tasks.
网络中的一种任务令牌，但实际上是这些任务的一半。
It makes sense because the question also has ac- is different for every example.
这是有道理的，因为每个例子的问题也都有所不同。
So this one here is natural language inference, NLI, uh,
所以这里的这个是自然语言推理，NLI，呃，
She covered also where we want to ask whether two sentences entail each other,
她还介绍了我们想问两个句子是否相互衔接的地方，
contradict each other or there's some neutral relationship between them.
相互矛盾或者它们之间存在一些中立的关系。
You've seen a lot of sentiment.
你已经看到了很多情绪。
And this here is kind of important.
这在这里很重要。
We actually asked is this sentence positive or negative versus just what is the sentiment
我们实际上问的是这句话是积极的还是消极的，而不是什么是情绪
and what- why that is important is that you see here in green,
什么 - 为什么重要的是你在这里看到绿色，
this answer here actually comes from
这里的答案实际上来自于
a word into question and if we formulate it that way,
一句话有问题，如果我们这样表达，
we can eventually do zero-shot learning where we ask a new question that was
我们最终可以做零射击学习，我们会问一个新的问题
never asked before for a new set of labels and magically, in some cases,
从来没有问过一套新标签，在某些情况下，神奇地，
it still actually works and we'll, you know,
它仍然有效，我们会，你知道，
ask que- we can ask questions like is this story happy or sad and it will still
问问 - 我们可以提出这样的问题，比如这个故事是幸福的还是悲伤的，它仍然存在
give us an answer even though we've never given
即使我们从未给过，也给我们一个答案
it a trained dataset of a bunch of happy and sad stories.
它是一系列快乐和悲伤故事的训练有素的数据集。
So, it's kind of zero-shot classification that you get to in
所以，这是你所接受的零射击分类
some cases if you formulate your questions in a way
在某些情况下，如果您以某种方式提出问题
that the answer is part as a word in the question.
答案是问题的一部分。
Then we have semantic role labeling here.
然后我们在这里有语义角色标记。
So what has something experienced, kind of a random weird question.
那么有什么经验，一种随机奇怪的问题。
Then we have a zero-shot relation extraction who is
然后我们有一个零射击关系提取
the illustrator of Cycle of the Werewolf,
狼人骑行的插画家，
we also have some dialogue state tracking.
我们还有一些对话状态跟踪。
What is the current state in- in a dialogue and the context just keeps on
对话中的当前状态是什么，上下文一直在继续
growing with the dialogue and then we also have SQL,
与对话一起成长，然后我们也有SQL，
Wiki SQL translation tasks but not translating into
Wiki SQL翻译任务但没有翻译成
another natural language translating into a SQL database query.
另一种自然语言转换为SQL数据库查询。
It's actually a super-helpful task.
这实际上是一项非常有用的任务。
There's a, you know, a lot of data out there that is stored in databases.
你知道，有很多数据存储在数据库中。
If you can access it without having to ask
如果你可以访问它而不必询问
somebody who knows how to program SQL it will make
有人知道如何编程SQL会有所作为
that data available to a lot more people so
这些数据可供更多人使用
they can analyze it and like business analytics and so on.
他们可以分析它，喜欢商业分析等等。
And then here, Winograd Schemas and anaphora resolution.
然后在这里，Winograd Schemas和anaphora决议。
Uh, some people call this kind of common sense reasoning but it's kind of,
呃，有些人称这种常识推理，但它有点像，
you know, mostly just anaphora resolution trying to understand in this context.
你知道，大多数只是在这种情况下试图理解的回指分辨率。
Uh, what -- who's, you know,
呃，什么 - 谁，你知道，
uh, the word like who had given help,
呃，像是谁给了帮助，
was it Susan or Joanne, and then based on this context,
是苏珊还是乔安妮，然后根据这个背景，
you can kind of should be able to figure that out and again here,
你可以在这里一次又一次地想到这一点，
the question is different for every single example. All right, yeah?
每个例子的问题都不同。好的，是吗？
When you're testing it -- like when you ask,
当你测试它时 - 就像你问的那样，
is this sentence positive or negative,
这句话是积极的还是消极的，
does it sometimes, like, [inaudible]?
有时会像[听不清]那样吗？
Great question. So, the question is when I ask,
好问题。所以，问题是我什么时候问，
is this sentence positive or negative will it sometimes eventually
这句话有时候是正面还是负面的
accidentally switch to a different one of the task and, uh,
不小心切换到另一个任务，呃，
we actually have a slide on that and the answer is it's surprisingly good at
我们实际上有一个幻灯片，答案是令人惊讶的擅长
knowing how to go about doing the task and where to get the answer where it's from.
知道如何完成任务以及从哪里获得答案。
Um, and yeah, they'll make more sense in a couple of slides once we go over the model.
嗯，是的，一旦我们越过模型，他们会在几张幻灯片中更有意义。
Any other questions about,
还有其他任何问题，
uh, the question answering formalism?
呃，回答形式主义的问题？
Are you able to formulate text generation in the question answer format as well?
您是否能够以问答形式制定文本生成？
Like, tell me a story.
比如，告诉我一个故事。
Good question. So can we do text generation, uh,
好问题。那么我们可以做文字生成，呃，
like tell me a story, uh,
比如告诉我一个故事，呃，
from a random kind of -- or in this kind of formalism.
从一种随机的 - 或在这种形式主义。
Uh, we don't have that as a task because largely it's really hard to evaluate.
呃，我们没有把它作为一项任务，因为在很大程度上它很难评估。
It'll tell you some random stuff and then is that a good story or not,
它会告诉你一些随机的东西然后是一个好故事，
is it grammatical, you have to come up with a lot of,
这是语法，你必须拿出很多，
uh, sort of, uh,
呃，有点，呃，
evaluation metrics which we actually are doing for
我们实际上正在做的评估指标
some of the dialogue systems and in case of dialogue,
一些对话系统，如果是对话，
why does -- why are they equivalent because
为什么 - 为什么它们相同，因为
the context can just keep on growing and every time, uh,
上下文可以继续增长，每次，呃，
the user said something, uh,
用户说了些什么，呃，
you basically try to then predict the next answer in that dialogue.
你基本上试着预测那个对话中的下一个答案。
And so I think you could very easily [NOISE] use this to generate texts.
所以我认为你很容易[噪音]使用它来生成文本。
Uh, you basically just ask -- tell it like what is, you know,
呃，你基本上只是问 - 告诉它是什么，你知道，
what's a good ending of the story and you maybe start the context with like
什么是故事的好结局，你可能会开始这样的背景
two or three words and then you ask the model to generate more and more words,
两三个单词，然后你要求模型生成越来越多的单词，
uh, in the form of this network I'll describe in a second. Yeah?
呃，在这个网络的形式，我将在一秒钟内描述。是吗？
I was wondering like, uh, when you're training
我想知道，呃，当你训练的时候
it and you're trying to research like a new task.
它和你正在尝试像新任务一样研究。
Uh, does it like learn with less data?
呃，是否喜欢用更少的数据学习？
That is an amazingly thoughtful question
这是一个非常有思想的问题
and it's- it's so important we'll have a bunch of slides on it.
它是如此重要，我们将有一堆幻灯片。
So maybe we'll- we'll go -- we'll continue and we'll get to that question, uh,
所以也许我们 - 我们会去 - 我们会继续，我们会回答这个问题，呃，
in a lot of detail because it's sort of why we're doing it and, the short answer is yes.
在很多细节上，因为这就是为什么我们这样做，简短的回答是肯定的。
But we'll get to more details. All right.
但我们会得到更多细节。行。
So these are basically the 10 tasks.
所以这些基本上就是10个任务。
Uh, and again this is the actual format for it.
呃，这又是它的实际格式。
So if you have a problem,
所以，如果你有问题，
and you can cast it in this format, uh,
你可以用这种格式投射它，呃，
you can just take, uh, the open source code and run it and,
你可以拿开源代码然后运行它，
uh, it'll- it'll work.
呃，它会工作的。
And so when you kind of analyze and think about what we've done here.
所以，当你分析并思考我们在这里所做的事情时。
In some ways, we've taken the tasks that
在某些方面，我们已经完成了任务
usually is kind of in your head but it's not given to the model.
通常是你的头脑，但它没有给模型。
The model is just given an input x and an output y in almost all of
几乎所有的模型都给出了输入x和输出y
the supervised systems and instead we're actually including the task in the inputs,
监督系统而不是我们实际上将任务包括在输入中，
uh, in the set of inputs to the model. So you can kind of call this meta-supervised learning.
呃，在模型的输入集合中。所以你可以称之为元监督学习。
So again the question, uh,
那么问题，呃，
is kind of our task definition for each of these different tasks.
是我们为这些不同任务中的每一个定义的任务。
The model has to figure out itself when to ask the question
该模型必须弄清楚何时提问
that way it can also figure out itself when to
这样它也可以自己搞清楚什么时候
transfer knowledge from these other tasks and y is again just the answer.
从这些其他任务转移知识，y再次只是答案。
So, in some ways it's meta-supervised learning and I'm quite excited
所以，在某种程度上它是元监督学习，我很兴奋
because once you allow the task to be given to the model as input,
因为一旦您允许将任务作为输入提供给模型，
it can kind of decide itself how to go about
它可以决定自己如何去做
solving that particular task and now you can learn,
解决这个特定的任务，现在你可以学习，
uh, a lot more powerful models.
呃，更强大的模特。
So once we had the dataset,
所以，一旦我们有了数据集，
we thought "Okay, how do we now solve this problem?"
我们想“好吧，我们现在如何解决这个问题？”
The simplest way is you could just say, "Well,
最简单的方法是你可以说，“嗯，
I have a big if statement,
我有一个很大的if声明，
I have a classifier in the beginning and then I classify.
我在开始时有一个分类器然后我分类。
If this is a machine translation task,
如果这是机器翻译任务，
then run my machine translation model."
然后运行我的机器翻译模型。“
And in general, in Python that would still be just like one big python,
一般来说，在Python中它仍然就像一个大蟒蛇，
uh, model with a bunch of if statements, right?
呃，带有一堆if语句的模型，对吧？
And that's not the goal because then we wouldn't get to any of
这不是目标，因为那时我们不会达到任何目标
the transfer learning and zero-shot capabilities that we're hoping for.
我们希望的转学和零射击能力。
So [NOISE] we want to have the model wanted
所以[NOISE]我们希望得到所需的模型
to have the capability to internally adjust
有能力进行内部调整
to these different tasks and make these decisions itself.
这些不同的任务，并自己做出这些决定。
And basically, all of those considerations and all
基本上，所有这些考虑因素和所有
of those thoughts led us, uh, to this model.
这些想法引导我们，呃，这个模型。
So before I go, uh,
所以在我走之前，呃，
into a little bit more detail.
更详细一点。
I'll just like sort of give you the high-level overview.
我只想给你一个高级概述。
Again, you start with the context.
再次，您从上下文开始。
Um, you start- you ask a question about, uh,
嗯，你开始 - 你问一个问题，呃，
that context document, and then we're going to generate,
那个上下文文档，然后我们要生成，
uh, the answer one word at a time by either pointing to the context,
呃，通过指向上下文，一次一个字的答案，
and you've had pointers already, right?
你已经有了指针，对吧？
Pointer networks, all that? Great. Um, pointing to a question word,
指针网络，这一切？大。嗯，指着一个问题词，
or choosing a word from an external vocabulary with your standard softmax classifier.
或使用标准softmax分类器从外部词汇表中选择一个单词。
Uh, and we'll have a pointer switch mechanism that will kind
呃，我们将有一个指针切换机制
of choose how much to weight [NOISE] each of these three generation mechanisms.
选择这三种机制中每一种的重量[NOISE]。
So, uh, let's dig into a little bit into this model.
所以，呃，让我们深入了解一下这个模型。
Fortunately, uh, in some ways it's kind of just taking the best, uh,
幸运的是，呃，在某些方面它只是采取最好的，呃，
of the current sort of the state of the art techniques and putting them together in a way,
当前那种最先进的技术并将它们组合在一起，
uh, that- that generalize well enough.
呃，那个 - 足够概括。
Uh, you can look at all the code on decanlp.com,
呃，你可以查看decanlp.com上的所有代码，
[NOISE] it has like thousands of, uh,
[NOISE]它有成千上万的，呃，
stars and, uh, and forks and stuff combined, uh,
明星，呃，叉子和东西结合在一起，呃，
and you can, you know,
你可以，你知道，
basically run everything, uh,
基本上运行一切，呃，
in this, uh, on these experiments with just one command.
在这个，呃，只用一个命令进行这些实验。
It'll double, you get all the datasets and everything and- and run everything,
它会加倍，你得到所有数据集和所有东西 - 并运行一切，
you can really explore what it looks like but let's- let's
你可以真正探索它的样子，但让我们来吧
dive a little bit into the details of what this model told us.
深入了解这个模型告诉我们的细节。
In some ways again, it just kind of takes
在某些方面，它只是需要
all the best ingredients from deep learning [NOISE] NLP,
所有最好的成分来自深度学习[NOISE] NLP，
most of which you've already learned about and puts them together in a reasonable way.
大多数你已经了解并以合理的方式将它们组合在一起。
So we start with fixed GloVe embeddings.
所以我们从固定的GloVe嵌入开始。
Eventually, we'll- we updated, uh,
最后，我们 - 我们更新了，呃，
the embeddings to CoVe embeddings, uh,
嵌入到CoVe嵌入中，呃，
and probably it'll work even better if you update them to BERT embeddings.
如果你把它们更新为BERT嵌入，它可能会更好。
Uh, but at some point we kind of have to move on and do other things.
呃，但在某些时候我们必须继续前进并做其他事情。
Uh, but basically, you have a fixed set of word vectors,
呃，但基本上，你有一套固定的单词向量，
and that is kind of important because in some of these,
这有点重要，因为在其中一些中，
uh, data sets, they're much smaller than others.
呃，数据集，它们比其他人小得多。
Uh, and as you know from SQuAD,
呃，正如你从SQUAD所知，
if you actually backpropagate into the word vectors,
如果你真的反向传播到单词向量，
you just do really, really well on your trained dataset,
你只是在训练有素的数据集上做得非常好，
but then you won't generalize because of most of the [NOISE] text,
但是由于大多数[NOISE]文本，你不会概括，
uh, test documents will include words you've never seen before.
呃，测试文件将包括你以前从未见过的单词。
So if you change all the word vectors during training, uh,
所以如果你在训练期间改变所有的单词向量，呃，
it won't- it won't work very well at test time and won't generalize the unseen words.
它不会 - 它在测试时不会很好地工作，也不会概括看不见的单词。
So, uh, fixed GloVe embeddings,
那么，嗯，固定GloVe嵌入，
if you don't have word vectors, uh,
如果你没有单词向量，呃，
for unseen words, we also have character n-gram embeddings.
对于看不见的单词，我们也有字符n-gram嵌入。
Then we pipe them through a simple linear layer,
然后我们通过一个简单的线性层管道，
and then we have a shared, uh,
然后我们有一个共享的，呃，
bidirectional LSTM with skip connections.
具有跳过连接的双向LSTM。
And so, uh, it's a deep- deep one so you skip to higher layers,
所以，呃，这是一个深刻的，所以你跳到更高层，
and it's shared between the context and the questions.
它在上下文和问题之间共享。
So they have basically the same [NOISE] set of weights.
所以它们基本上具有相同的[NOISE]权重集。
[NOISE] Then, uh, we have a co-attention layer.
[NOISE]然后，呃，我们有一个共同关注层。
Uh, where we basically just have outer products, uh,
呃，我们基本上只有外用产品，呃，
between all the hidden states of those two sequences,
在这两个序列的所有隐藏状态之间，
and again, have skip connections, uh,
再次，跳过连接，呃，
to circumvent, uh, those as well.
那些也是为了规避那些人。
So now you have kind of context or question dependent, uh,
所以现在你有某种背景或问题依赖，呃，
contextual representations [NOISE] or- or representations of that context.
上下文表示[NOISE]或 - 或该上下文的表示。
[NOISE] Uh, then we feed those into our transformer layers,
[NOISE]呃，然后我们将它们送入我们的变压器层，
uh, and we actually tried to use transformers for all the things,
呃，我们实际上试图将变形金刚用于所有事情，
with having no LSTMs or any of that.
没有LSTM或其中任何一个。
Uh, unfortunately, transformer layers were still, uh,
呃，不幸的是，变压器层还在，呃，
very, uh, finicky and very hard to optimize,
非常，呃，挑剔，很难优化，
and there's a lot of trickery with- of the learning rates,
学习率有很多诡计，
and we could just not get them to perform really well,
我们可能无法让他们表现得非常好，
uh, on- on these 10 different tasks.
呃，这10个不同的任务。
Uh, [NOISE] sometimes you had one transformer layer, one transformer network,
呃，[NOISE]有时你有一个变压器层，一个变压器网络，
that worked really well in one task,
在一项任务中表现得非常好，
but the only other transformer network that worked well
但是唯一运行良好的其他变压器网络
on the second task had like half the layers.
在第二个任务就像一半的层。
And once you tried to have one network with the same number of layers,
一旦你试图让一个网络具有相同的层数，
it just wouldn't work on either of the two tasks anymore.
它只是不再适用于这两个任务中的任何一个。
Uh, and so- so yeah, unfortunately as nice as they
呃，所以是的，不幸的是，他们很好
are because they're nicely paralyzable in GPUs,
是因为它们在GPU中很好地瘫痪了，
uh, they weren't yet robust enough,
呃，他们还不够健壮，
uh, to- to be used for this.
呃，为此而使用。
[NOISE] So we have to have these LSTMs,
[NOISE]所以我们必须拥有这些LSTM，
uh, before and after the transformer layers.
呃，在变压器层之前和之后。
[NOISE] And then we essentially just have a standard sort of autoregressive, uh,
[NOISE]然后我们基本上只有一种标准的自回归，呃，
decoder where given the last state,
解码器给出最后一个状态，
uh, we generate the next word.
呃，我们生成下一个单词。
And then we have these three pointer mechanisms.
然后我们有这三个指针机制。
Uh, they're very similar to the pointer ne- mechanisms you already know.
呃，它们与你已经知道的指针机制非常相似。
But now on top of these very contextualized representations, uh,
但是现在除了这些非常情境化的表示之外，呃，
at the end of this encoder, uh,
在这个编码器的末尾，呃，
and it basically learns to either point to question words,
并且它基本上学会了指向提问词，
context words based on the hidden states,
基于隐藏状态的上下文单词，
or have also a standard softmax,
或者还有一个标准的softmax，
and then we just basically have a weighted sum,
然后我们基本上有一个加权和，
convex sum, of these three different distributions of output words.
凸三和，这三种不同的输出词分布。
[NOISE] All right.
[NOISE]好的。
So I think these are mostly standard components that you've already saw,
所以我认为这些都是你已经看过的标准组件，
uh, for you- already seen all their details.
呃，对你来说 - 已经看过他们所有的细节了。
But if you have any questions,
但如果您有任何疑问，
um, about how we put it together? Yeah?
嗯，关于我们如何把它放在一起？是吗？
[NOISE] So the output- the output has to be a word.
[NOISE]所以输出 - 输出必须是一个单词。
That's right. The output has to be a word and it's always either a word from the context,
那就对了。输出必须是一个单词，它始终是上下文中的一个单词，
a word from the question or a word from the softmax.
来自问题的单词或来自softmax的单词。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
That's- the data preprocessing I guess it's different with each task.
那 - 数据预处理我猜它与每个任务不同。
So the data preprocessing is different for each task,
因此，每项任务的数据预处理都是不同的，
but we basically had to normalize everything to have
但我们基本上必须规范化所有东西
the same tokenization and- and all of that. [NOISE]
相同的标记化 - 以及所有这些。 [噪声]
Uh, so do the double arrows in the encoding just represent there's a bidirectional?
呃，编码中的双箭头也表示双向？
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
Yeah. But the double arrows,
是啊。但双箭头，
uh, here are just bidirectional.
呃，这里只是双向的。
So left to right and right to left for the LSTMs. All right.
所以LSTM从左到右依次为左右。行。
So what datasets, uh, are we using?
那么我们使用的数据集是什么？
Uh, I mentioned that that was a big headache in the beginning.
呃，我提到这一开始很头疼。
Uh, we definitely wanted to include a lot of the sequence to
呃，我们肯定想要包含很多序列
sequence tasks that we felt like are very,
我们觉得非常的序列任务，
um, sort of high level and I- immediately useful, uh,
嗯，有点高水平，我 - 立即有用，呃，
and in some ways what this also shows you is that
在某些方面，这也向你展示了这一点
nowadays you don't have to work as much on some of the intermediate representations,
如今你不必在一些中间表示上工作，
uh, in NLP anymore.
呃，在NLP了。
Uh, you can just directly go for the end tasks that that real users might care about,
呃，你可以直接去寻找真实用户可能关心的最终任务，
and then have these end-to-end trainable systems,
然后有这些端到端的可训练系统，
uh, that really do quite well.
呃，真的很好。
And, uh, I've myself worked a lot on parsing.
而且，呃，我自己在解析方面做了很多工作。
And so I don't wanna, you know,
所以我不想，你知道，
say we- we don't need it.
说我们 - 我们不需要它。
There's certainly still tasks that you do need it for,
肯定还有你需要的任务，
but it's kind of surprising that you can just go directly to translation or summarization
但令人惊讶的是，您可以直接进行翻译或摘要
without having intermediate representations that
没有中间表示
were sort of very specifically hand-designed.
有点特别是手工设计的。
Um, so we had those three really interesting, uh, and hard tasks.
嗯，所以我们有三个非常有趣，呃和艰巨的任务。
Question answering, machine translation, summarization.
问答，机器翻译，总结。
They actually also have the three biggest datasets,
他们实际上也有三个最大的数据集，
uh, of all of these.
呃，所有这些。
Uh, then we had NLI, and basically, um,
呃，那我们有NLI，基本上，嗯，
all of these, uh, 10 datasets [NOISE] were, uh,
所有这些，呃，10个数据集[NOISE]，呃，
publicly available, uh, and in several cases especially for translation,
公开，呃，在某些情况下特别是翻译，
you could actually find much larger, uh, translation datasets,
你真的可以找到更大的呃翻译数据集，
but we also tried to keep it, uh,
但我们也试着保留它，呃，
to a- to a size where normal people that don't work in gigantic companies with huge, uh,
到一个普通人不能在巨大的公司工作的规模，呃，
GPU infrastructures could still run experiments, [NOISE] uh, themselves.
GPU基础设施仍然可以进行实验，[NOISE]呃，他们自己。
So universities and folks, uh, can still run it on.
所以大学和民众，呃，仍然可以继续运作。
Basically if you have just a single GPU,
基本上如果你只有一个GPU，
it'll probably take about a week or so, uh,
它可能需要大约一个星期左右，呃，
to run an experiment.
进行实验。
If you have multiple GPUs on one large AWS machine,
如果您在一台大型AWS计算机上有多个GPU，
you can kind of run an experiment in a day or two.
你可以在一两天内进行实验。
And so especially for translation, right,
对于翻译尤其如此，对，
you could get a lot more data, uh, than IWSLT.
你可以获得比IWSLT更多的数据，呃。
And each of these, uh,
而且每一个，呃，
communities and datasets and- and tasks has their own metric.
社区和数据集和任务都有自己的指标。
We actually tried to, in the beginning,
我们实际上试图在开始时
we had a lot of discussion about how we should
我们有很多关于我们应该怎么做的讨论
define the measure of success for this project.
定义该项目的成功衡量标准。
Uh, it doesn't make sense, uh,
呃，这没有意义，呃，
to have a normalized F1 score for basically all the different tasks,
基本上所有不同的任务都有一个标准化的F1分数，
but then we basically realized that
但后来我们基本上意识到了
these different communities have different metrics for a reason.
这些不同的社区有不同的指标是有原因的。
Uh, unfortunately at least all of these metrics are from 0-100 in theory.
呃，不幸的是，至少所有这些指标在理论上都是0-100。
Of course, in practice, you rarely ever see, uh,
当然，在实践中，你很少见到，呃，
a translation system of a 100, uh,
一个100的翻译系统，呃，
or even high 90s of a BLEU score,
甚至高达90分的BLEU分数，
uh, or these really, really high ROUGE scores.
呃，或者这些确实非常高的ROUGE分数。
But, you know, in theory they go from 0-100, and so, uh,
但是，你知道，理论上他们从0到100，所以，呃，
we kept basically intact the different evaluation metrics for each of these communities,
我们基本保持每个社区的不同评估指标，
and we just said we're going to sum them up.
我们只是说我们要总结一下。
And, uh, when we first talked about this,
而且，呃，当我们第一次谈到这个时，
we have- had a lot of discussion,
我们有很多讨论，
uh, with- with others also like, oh,
呃，和其他人一样也喜欢，哦，
but translation is so much more important because it's much
但翻译是如此重要，因为它很多
bigger and it's a much more useful task than you still,
更大，这是一个比你更有用的任务，
you know, silly like pronoun resolution Winograd Schemas
你知道吗，愚蠢的代名词解决Winograd Schemas
which only have a couple hundred training samples.
只有几百个训练样本。
And so you should have weighted translation more and
所以你应该更多地加权翻译
then literally five questions later somebody's like,
那么后来有人提出了五个问题，
"Why didn't you weight pronoun resolution more?
“你为什么不加重代词决议？
That is a really hard task that captures sort of common sense reasoning and, you know,
这是一项非常艰巨的任务，可以捕捉到一些常识推理，你知道，
the complexity of language and semantics,
语言和语义的复杂性，
and unlike all this, like, statistical pattern matching [NOISE] that you do in translation."
并且不像所有这些，比如你在翻译中所做的统计模式匹配[NOISE]。“
And I was like, I used to talk to that guy [LAUGHTER] and like,
而我就像，我曾经和那个人谈过[笑声]并喜欢，
uh, hopefully in the end,
呃，希望最后，
we'll just all agree that like it's reasonable to sum them up, uh,
我们都会同意，总结它们是合理的，呃，
and of course, you also have to tackle when you run experiments in this.
当然，当你在这里进行实验时，你也必须解决这个问题。
Uh, a lot of the complexity that you have in machine learning and,
呃，你在机器学习中有很多复杂性，
you know, stuff that very few people talk about like having very skewed distributions.
你知道的，很少有人谈论的东西，比如非常倾斜的发行版。
So you have translation which has, uh,
所以你有翻译，有，呃，
millions or hundreds of thousands of examples,
数百万或数十万个例子，
and you have Winograd Schemas,
你有Winograd Schemas，
uh, that only have a couple hundred.
呃，那只有几百个。
How do you train that such that you don't just completely ignore the smaller dataset.
你是如何训练的，这样你就不会完全忽略较小的数据集。
Uh, so we'll get to some of the optimization trickery,
呃，所以我们会得到一些优化技巧，
uh, that Nitish spent several months on in a bit.
呃，Nitish花了好几个月的时间。
But I first wanna sort of give you the first set of experiments.
但我首先想给你第一组实验。
So as you can see from all the numbers,
从所有数字中可以看出，
there's a lot of experiments, uh,
有很多实验，呃，
that we ran to even get to this,
我们甚至跑到这里，
and so we'll walk through this, uh, quite carefully.
所以我们会仔细研究这个，呃。
I think hopefully you'll get some ideas also for- for ablations,
我希望你也会得到一些关于消融的想法，
or experiments that you might wanna run in your, um,
或者你可能想要在你的实验中运行的实验，嗯，
in your experiments and in your,
在你的实验和你的，
uh, problem- final- final projects.
呃，问题 ​​- 最终决赛项目。
So what are we looking at here?
那么我们在这看什么呢？
So basically, uh, on the left side,
所以基本上，呃，在左侧，
we have single task performance.
我们有单一的任务表现。
So here, each number comes from its different model that was trained,
所以在这里，每个数字来自其训练的不同模型，
um, separately on just one task.
嗯，单独完成一项任务。
Uh, each row- each column here is the same architecture, uh,
呃，每一行 - 这里的每一列都是相同的架构，呃，
and [NOISE] on the right side here,
和右边的[NOISE]，
we basically have, uh,
我们基本上有，呃，
for each column is basically the same architecture and the same exact model.
对于每列基本上是相同的架构和相同的精确模型。
So here, we have four different models and here, uh,
所以在这里，我们有四种不同的模型，在这里，呃，
we have 40 different models,
我们有40种不同的型号，
and each column again is the same architecture.
并且每列再次是相同的架构。
And so the simplest, uh,
所以最简单的，呃，
first column here is just a standard sequence to sequence
这里的第一列只是序列的标准序列
model with very few bells and whistles and some pointers,
模型很少有铃声和口哨声和一些指针，
but nothing sort of major.
但没什么大不了的。
It's pretty deep, you know,
你知道，这很深
stack bidirectional LSTM skip connections,
堆栈双向LSTM跳过连接，
all the standard good well-tuned stuff for sequence to sequence models.
序列到序列模型的所有标准的良好调整的东西。
And, uh, then we added self-attention.
而且，呃，然后我们增加了自我关注。
Um, this- this sort of, uh,
嗯，这 - 这种，呃，
basically, uh, transformer layers.
基本上，呃，变压器层。
[NOISE] Then we have this co-attention layer of
[NOISE]然后我们有这个共同关注层
the outer products that we mentioned in the beginning,
我们在开始时提到的外部产品，
and then we also added the question pointer.
然后我们还添加了问题指针。
So having the ability to point to a word in a question.
因此有能力指出问题中的单词。
All right. Any questions about this table?
行。有关此表的任何问题吗？
We'll dig into some of the details.
我们将深入研究一些细节。
Uh, okay. Well, we'll dig into
呃，好的。好吧，我们将深入研究
the details first and then maybe you can think of some questions.
首先是细节，然后你可以想到一些问题。
So let's analyze, uh,
那么让我们分析，呃，
what's going on in this table because there are a lot of numbers, uh,
这张桌子上发生了什么，因为有很多数字，呃，
and you really want to carefully analyze and sort of distinguish.
而你真的想仔细分析和区分。
I think my first, uh,
我想我的第一个，呃，
observation was, wow, we can have a single architecture.
观察是，哇，我们可以有一个单一的架构。
Like, even, even this is not quite what we want, right?
就像，甚至，即使这不是我们想要的，对吗？
We want a single model.
我们想要一个单一的模型。
But even this kind of showed us, wow,
但即使是这样的表现我们，哇，
you can have a single architecture that actually does really well and somewhat randomly,
你可以拥有一个实际上非常好并且有点随机的架构
in some cases, it actually had gotten state-of-the-art results.
在某些情况下，它实际上已经获得了最先进的结果。
So Wiki SQL, for instance,
所以维基SQL，例如，
this architecture had the best model
这种架构有最好的模型
to translate natural language English questions into SQL queries,
将自然语言英语问题翻译成SQL查询，
which was a surprise to us because it is the ninth dataset.
这对我们来说是一个惊喜，因为它是第九个数据集。
It was really not like a priority for us and when we designed
对我们来说，当我们设计时，它确实不是优先考虑的事情
the model and thought about how to generate words and pointer mechanisms and so on.
关于如何生成单词和指针机制等的模型和思考。
We just kind of had the standard context of SQL words
我们只是有一些SQL词的标准上下文
and we asked the question what's the translation to SQL, and then, uh,
我们问了什么是SQL的翻译问题，然后，呃，
somewhat surprisingly to us this particular architecture had the state-of-the-art, uh,
有点令人惊讶的是，这个特殊的建筑有最先进的，呃，
on SQL generation and bunch of folks in that community kind
关于SQL生成和那种社区中的一群人
of picked it up more quickly because it had state-of-the-art.
因为它具有最先进的技术，所以能够更快地完成它。
And that's- uh, unfortunately,
而且，不幸的是，
it doesn't have that many other state-of-the-art numbers, uh,
它没有那么多其他最先进的数字，呃，
which is why it's harder, uh,
这就是为什么它更难，呃，
it's actually a much harder task.
这实际上是一项艰巨的任务。
And what you also observe is that,
你还观察到的是，
uh, in several of the cases, uh,
呃，在几个案例中，呃，
using the multitask model,
使用多任务模型，
so having a single model for all the 10 tasks,
所以对所有10个任务都有一个模型，
uh, actually hurts performance at first.
呃，实际上一开始就伤害了表现。
And this is also something you rarely read in papers because papers
这也是你很少在论文中读到的东西，因为论文
have a strong selection bias to only publish positive results.
有强烈的选择偏见，只能发布积极的结果。
Uh, and when you look at most transfer learning and multitask learning papers,
呃，当你看大多数转学和多任务学习论文时，
they're sort of an outside of the actual model consideration of like,
他们有点像实际的模型考虑因素，
well, let's only combine tasks that we know will work well with one another.
好吧，让我们只结合我们知道相互配合良好的任务。
And if they don't work and hurt performance,
如果他们不工作并伤害表现，
then we'd just exclude them from our experiments.
然后我们将它们从我们的实验中排除。
And so you don't see many negative task results, uh,
所以你没有看到很多负面的任务结果，呃，
in the literature and there are a few papers here and there that, uh,
在文献中，这里和那里有一些论文，呃，
study basically the opposite side of transfer learning and that is,
研究基本上是转学习的另一面，也就是说，
uh, catastrophic interference and catastrophic forgetting.
呃，灾难性的干扰和灾难性的遗忘。
So interference is when you train two different tasks in the same model,
因此干扰就是当你在同一个模型中训练两个不同的任务时，
and to interfere with one another next, you hurt each other's performance.
然后彼此干扰，你伤害了彼此的表现。
And catastrophic forgetting is if you train continually
如果你不断训练就会发生灾难性遗忘
your first train in one task then you train on a second task,
你的第一列火车在一项任务中然后你训练第二项任务，
people used to think,
人们曾经认为，
"Oh, well, you know,
“哦，嗯，你知道，
basically the first task will be completely
基本上第一项任务将是完全的
forgotten," and you just work well on the second task.
忘记了，“你只是在第二项任务上工作得很好。
If you train neural networks sort of in a sequential way one task and then
如果你按照顺序的方式训练神经网络，那么就是一个任务
another and somewhat surprisingly, uh,
另一个有点令人惊讶的是，呃，
we- we found that things aren't actually
我们 - 我们发现事实并非如此
catastrophically being forgotten in these models,
在这些模型中灾难性地被遗忘，
turns out that if you train them sequentially and
事实证明，如果你按顺序训练它们
you add a little bit of the original to the first task,
你为第一个任务添加了一点原创，
it comes back very, very quickly.
它非常非常快地回来了。
So while the performance is really bad,
所以虽然表现非常糟糕，
you can get to the really good performance very,
你可以得到非常好的表现，
very quickly in very few iterations.
很快迭代很快。
So but it's one of the many interesting sort of tidbits that we found,
所以，这是我们发现的许多有趣的花絮之一，
uh, in the course of this that we haven't even published yet. All right.
呃，在此期间我们还没有发表。行。
So, uh, focusing on, uh,
所以，呃，专注于，呃，
the transformer layers here we basically find transformers
这里的变压器层我们基本上找到变压器
do help the original sequence to sequence model a lot.
帮助原始序列对序列进行大量排序。
So if you tune them carefully and you combine them with, uh,
所以，如果你仔细调整它们并将它们与它们结合起来，呃，
some bidirectional LSTMs and so on, uh,
一些双向LSTM等等，呃，
they were very helpful and improved, uh,
他们非常有帮助和改进，呃，
across a bunch of different datasets, in some cases quite significantly.
跨越一堆不同的数据集，在某些情况下非常显着。
Another observation is question-answering and semantic role labeling,
另一个观察是问答和语义角色标记，
uh, actually can predict each other's performance quite well.
呃，实际上可以很好地预测对方的表现。
If one works well, the other works well,
如果一个运作良好，另一个运作良好，
uh, and- and vice-versa.
呃，反之亦然。
If they don't work well,
如果它们不能很好地工作，
uh, both of them don't work very well.
呃，他们俩都行不通。
Um, and it's also interesting because both of those tasks have different questions for,
嗯，这也很有趣，因为这两个任务都有不同的问题，
uh, every training example.
呃，每个训练的例子。
Pointing. Uh, so the question pointing,
指点。呃，所以问题指出，
uh, is super important.
呃，非常重要。
Uh, we actually have in some cases, uh,
呃，我们实际上在某些情况下，呃，
twice the performance even for,
性能提高两倍，
and this is kind of surprising to us,
这对我们来说很奇怪，
a simple classification task where you could just have a standard Softmax.
一个简单的分类任务，你可以有一个标准的Softmax。
But instead of saying you have a Softmax of entailment, contradiction, and so on,
但不是说你有一个蕴涵，矛盾等的Softmax，
you just basically, uh,
你基本上，呃，
point to the word entailment in the question.
指出问题中的蕴涵一词。
And that was also the case for Winograd Schemas that also benefited a lot,
对于Winograd Schemas来说，情况也是如此，这也使得受益匪浅，
uh, from this pointer mechanism.
呃，从这个指针机制。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Can you explain that?
你能解释一下吗？
Sure. Um, can we explain it? Why-
当然。嗯，我们可以解释一下吗？为什么-
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Why does it help so much?
为什么这么有用呢？
Um, in some ways,
嗯，在某些方面，
I think partly is the whole architecture
我认为部分是整个架构
has been gotten- has gotten better and better at pointing.
已经得到了更好，更好的指点。
And part of the reason we actually do very,
部分原因我们实际上做得非常好，
very poorly in translation,
翻译很差，
which is the only task that hurt in the- our first experiments a lot, uh,
这是我们第一次实验中唯一受伤的任务，呃，
in the multitask setting is that that is the only task that now has to generate,
在多任务设置中，这是现在必须生成的唯一任务，
uh, results from a completely separate Softmax,
呃，完全独立的Softmax的结果，
whereas the rest of the architecture got really,
而其他建筑真的，
really good at pointing to things to answer questions, any kind of question.
真的善于指点回答问题的事情，任何一种问题。
Uh, and so but in some ways,
呃，但在某些方面，
I think that is one explanation,
我认为这是一个解释，
but I- I don't think it's- it's all of it.
但我 - 我不认为这就是全部。
I think we still need to figure out more why this happens. All right.
我想我们仍然需要弄清楚为什么会发生这种情况。行。
Now, multitask learning is the most
现在，多任务学习是最多的
helpful when it comes to zero-shot and I'm actually very excited about that.
在零射击方面很有帮助，我其实非常兴奋。
So this is a zero-shot relation extraction where you have different kinds of, uh,
所以这是一个零镜头关系提取，你有不同的类型，呃，
relations that you might wanna extract and you might have never
你可能想要提取的关系，你可能永远不会
seen like the student-teacher relationship that you're trying
看起来像你正在尝试的师生关系
to identify in a certain context or
在某种情况下识别或识别
a product company relationship or something like that.
产品公司的关系或类似的东西。
And so, uh, that one actually, uh,
所以，呃，那个，其实，呃，
benefited a lot and almost got twice, uh,
受益匪浅，几乎得了两次，呃，
as high in terms of the accuracy, uh,
在准确性方面，呃，
when you learned it with everything else.
当你用其他一切来学习它的时候。
So these were questions, it's never seen before,
所以这些都是问题，这是以前从未见过的，
relations that it's never seen before,
以前从未见过的关系，
and it got twice as good, uh,
它有两倍的好，呃，
and benefited a lot especially from having seen other kinds of questions.
并且特别是从看过其他类型的问题中受益匪浅。
And in some ways, we have to give a lot of credit to SQuAD too,
在某些方面，我们也必须给SQUAD很多功劳，
uh, because SQuAD as a dataset,
呃，因为SQuAD是一个数据集，
uh, kind of pushed people into thinking about pointers as a mechanism to generate answers.
呃，有点推动人们将指针作为一种机制来产生答案。
And pointers, we kind of see them like as a given and they don't get that much credit,
和指针，我们看到他们像一个给定的，他们没有得到那么多的功劳，
but they allow you to predict answers that you've never seen before at training time.
但是它们可以让你预测在训练时从未见过的答案。
To generate words, you've never seen before at training time,
为了生成单词，你在训练时从未见过，
which is actually quite- quite amazing. All right.
这实际上相当惊人。行。
Now, the main observation though
现在，主要观察虽然
here is that you still if you had an Oracle that would tell you
如果你有一个可以告诉你的Oracle，那么你仍然可以
exactly which task you're currently in
你目前在哪个任务
and you would be perfectly kind of separating these into 10 different models,
你会完全将它们分成10个不同的模型，
maybe they're all the same architecture but there's still 10 different models, then, uh,
也许他们都是相同的建筑，但仍然有10种不同的模型，那么，呃，
you would actually still do slightly better,
你实际上还会做得稍好一点，
uh, than the first version of this multitask learning model.
呃，比这个多任务学习模型的第一个版本。
And that is largely because we
这主要是因为我们
chose to include a bunch of different tasks that have nothing to do
选择包括一堆无关的任务
with one another and we wanted the community to start
彼此之间，我们希望社区开始
thinking about tackling catastrophic interference, right?
想着解决灾难性的干扰吧？
If you learn like a new language or, you know,
如果你像新语言一样学习，或者你知道，
you learn how to understand social media on Twitter,
你学习如何理解Twitter上的社交媒体，
you don't replace all your language,
你没有替换所有的语言，
uh, you know, in- in your brain.
呃，你知道，在你的脑子里。
You have one brain, it keeps getting smarter,
你有一个大脑，它会越来越聪明，
you keep learning new skills,
你不断学习新技能，
even when that skills that are new to you are very,
即使那些对你不熟悉的技能非常
very different from old skills.
与旧技能截然不同。
So in some ways we may have made our lives too hard,
所以在某些方面我们可能会让我们的生活变得艰难，
and now we're actually thinking, okay,
现在我们真的在想，好吧，
maybe if you wanna publish a nicer paper on multitask learning,
也许如果你想发表关于多任务学习的更好的论文，
we'll just look at all the tasks that do help each other,
我们只看看所有相互帮助的任务，
and then we'll just, you know, have groups of tasks,
然后我们只是，你知道，有一组任务，
and then I can very quickly publish,
然后我可以很快发布，
uh, some, some nice state-of-the-art papers.
呃，有些，一些不错的最新论文。
But basically here, uh, we're still, uh,
但基本上在这里，呃，我们还是，呃，
quite significantly away in the decaScore between 10 different models and a single model.
10个不同模型和单个模型之间的decaScore相当显着。
Now, this of course is kind of an oracle score,
现在，这当然是一种oracle得分，
that's why we put it in parentheses because you don't actually have this oracle.
这就是为什么我们把它放在括号中，因为你实际上没有这个神谕。
And in some cases,
在某些情况下，
it's quite easy to build an almost perfect classifier.
建立一个近乎完美的分类器非常容易。
So, you know, separating what is the summary
所以，你知道，分离什么是摘要
based on that question and what is the translation from English to German,
基于这个问题以及从英语到德语的翻译是什么，
you can do with almost 100 percent accuracy.
你几乎可以100％准确地做到。
Uh, but, uh, SQuAD, question-answering,
呃，但是，呃，SQUAD，问答，
and zero-shot relation extraction,
和零射击关系提取，
and question-answering as a semantic role labeling,
和问答作为语义角色标签，
those are actually easily confused in terms of how
这些实际上很容易混淆
to generate the answers and you wouldn't quite know,
产生答案，你不会知道，
uh, which into which model to route, uh, this.
呃，哪个模型要路由，呃，这个。
So in some sense, this is kind of theoretical. All right.
所以在某种意义上说，这是一种理论。行。
Now, I mentioned that we have this prob- this
现在，我提到我们有这个问题
complexity in the optimization strategy and this is one of the many,
优化策略的复杂性，这是众多的，
um, sort of problems that don't get that much, uh, coverage.
嗯，那些没有那么多的问题，呃，报道。
But when you have a very,
但是，当你有一个，
uh, imbalanced or skewed dataset,
呃，不平衡或偏斜的数据集，
it's easy to lose track and basically overpower the smaller dataset tasks.
很容易失去跟踪并且基本上压倒了较小的数据集任务。
And so, uh, the first, uh,
所以，呃，第一个，呃，
simplest training- we actually tried a ton of different training strategies,
最简单的培训 - 我们实际上尝试了大量不同的培训策略，
but in the end, this fully joint one worked quite well.
但最终，这个完全联合的工作得很好。
But actually promised to ask go wait for questions, uh, on this table.
但实际上答应要求等待问题，呃，在这张桌子上。
So any questions on all these results so far? Yeah?
那么到目前为止对所有这些结果的问题呢？是吗？
So, uh, [NOISE] since you mentioned that if you had
所以，呃，[NOISE]，因为你提到过，如果你有
an oracle that will tell you which task it is and
一个oracle，它会告诉你它是哪个任务
you have two better ways having 10 different ones.
你有两种更好的方法，有10种不同的方法。
So really try training a model on
所以真的尝试训练模型
like data meaning what task is interested in this particular version?
喜欢数据意味着什么任务对这个特定版本感兴趣？
We did. And so it- it confused, you know,
我们做到了。所以它很困惑，你知道，
SQuAD and- and those too the quest- the other- basically the other,
SQUAD和 - 那些太过任务 - 另一个 - 基本上是另一个，
uh, two types of problems that were also cast, ask question answering.
呃，还有两类问题，请问问答。
So it confused those.
所以它混淆了那些。
Um, but then a lot of the others, it was able to like, very perfectly do it.
嗯，但后来很多其他人，它能够非常完美地做到这一点。
But then you basically, as soon as you,
但是你基本上，只要你，
uh, were to try to then build a whole model and get a decaScore,
呃，试着建立一个完整的模型并获得decaScore，
if your- if your classifier is even like 90 percent accurate,
如果您 - 如果您的分类器甚至准确度为90％，
you basically multiply this by 0,9 and
你基本上乘以0,9和
you get dinged so hard that it- it's not competitive anymore.
你得到了很大的努力，以至于它不再具有竞争力了。
So it is actually hard if you try to just build
所以如果你试着建立它实际上很难
that whole system and keep adding sort of if-then else statements,
整个系统并继续添加if-then else语句，
uh, to make that, uh,
呃，做那个，呃，
into sort of a single system. Yeah?
成为一个单一的系统。是吗？
Have you tried telling the model what kind of task this it's doing,
你有没有试过告诉模特它正在做什么样的任务，
just giving that indicator of the kind of task quickly?
只是快速给出那种任务的指标？
I mean, in some ways,
我的意思是，在某些方面，
we did in this case,
我们在这种情况下做了，
because we only trained each model separately on it.
因为我们只分别训练每个模型。
[inaudible]
[听不见]
Um, only through the question.
嗯，只能通过这个问题。
Yeah. Because I was thinking the
是啊。因为我在想
um, maybe it's not that important that the model figure out what we want it to
嗯，也许模型找出我们想要的东西并不重要
do in- in a practical [NOISE] application
进入实际的[NOISE]应用程序
if we could just tell it what we want it to do right now?
如果我们能告诉它我们现在想做什么？
In some cases, you could tell.
在某些情况下，你可以说。
Uh, so the question is sort of,
呃，问题就是这样，
uh, and even in the multitask setting,
呃，甚至在多任务设置中，
you could have like an extra kind of token to say,
你可能想要一种额外的令牌，
"Now, you're doing summarization.
“现在，你正在进行总结。
So, and that's another input."
所以，这是另一个输入。“
Uh, in some ways,
呃，在某些方面，
whether you have a summarization token,
你是否有一个摘要令牌，
uh, or you ask what is the summary?
呃，或者你问一下总结是什么？
It actually I don't think makes that big of a difference.
实际上我并不认为这有很大的不同。
It's just now you can query this model in
现在你可以查询这个模型了
very natural language rather than having to know
非常自然的语言，而不是必须知道
kind of a special token to, to query the model.
查询模型的一种特殊标记。
Uh, and we'll see actually in a couple of slides that the model is not confused,
呃，我们会在几张幻灯片中看到模型没有混淆，
uh, when it comes to how to generate the answers.
呃，谈到如何产生答案。
So, for every of the task,
所以，对于每一项任务，
it knows very clearly how to generate the words to get to the right,
它非常清楚地知道如何生成要到达右边的单词，
to get to, you know, a reasonably accurate answer.
你知道，这是一个相当准确的答案。
[NOISE] Um, in the- [inaudible] does the model
[NOISE]嗯，在 -  [听不清]中做模型
see all of the data and then [inaudible] that class or does it only include a [inaudible]?
看到所有的数据，然后[音​​频不清晰]该类或它只包括[音频不清晰]？
Oh, great question. So, how do we train, uh, the single task models?
哦，很好的问题。那么，我们如何训练，呃，单一任务模型？
They're only trained on that dataset.
他们只接受过该数据集的培训。
So, the SQuAD number here is just a single model that has only seen SQuAD training.
所以，这里的SQuAD数字只是一个只见过SQuAD训练的模型。
[NOISE] So, your point about the,
[NOISE]所以，你的观点是，
um, the pointer exception for the, uh,
嗯，指针异常，呃，
[inaudible] generally more helpful than [inaudible]?
[听不清]通常比[听不清]更有帮助？
Somewhat surprisingly, even, ah,
有点令人惊讶，甚至，啊，
in the case here, uh,
在这种情况下，呃，
where we had, um, this is MultiNLI,
我们在哪里，嗯，这是MultiNLI，
this particular model, I mean,
这个特殊的模型，我的意思是，
if you just have the standard sequence to sequence,
如果你只是有序列的标准序列，
it just generates, you know,
它只会产生，你知道，
also with a softmax, uh, that label.
还有一个softmax，呃，那个标签。
So in that sense, it's quite similar.
所以在这个意义上，它非常相似。
Uh, but yeah, it was actually better able to just point, which actually led us, uh,
呃，但是，它实际上更能指出，这实际上引导了我们，呃，
for a while into thinking about maybe we should have a project where we just say point to
考虑一下我们应该有一个我们只是说点的项目
all the things and just get rid of softmax classifiers forever.
所有的事情，永远摆脱softmax分类器。
Um, the problem is when you then try to do translation also,
嗯，问题是当你尝试做翻译时，
it's like okay wow,
好像哇哇，
what do you point to,
你指的是什么
and then you kind of pre-train it and do
然后你就开始训练它了
some alignment and it gets kinda very large and you point to a lot of different like,
一些对齐，它有点非常大，你指向很多不同的像，
you may have like- like tens of thousands of potential candidates.
你可能喜欢成千上万的潜在候选人。
So we kinda discarded it as like a single unifying model for all the things,
所以我们把它丢弃，就像所有东西的单一统一模型一样，
but you could point to a lot of different,
但你可以指出很多不同的，
like a lot of these tasks,
像很多这些任务，
you could actually point to and
你实际上可以指向和
I think it's another interesting side project that could spawn from this, yeah.
我认为这是另一个有趣的侧面项目，可以从中产生，是的。
Just a quick question to how,
只是一个简单的问题，如何，
how sensitive [inaudible] how sensitive, uh,
多么敏感[听不清]多么敏感，呃，
the individual components [inaudible] was when you
个别组件[听不清]就在你的时候
slightly perturb the relative weights of them in the loss function?
在损失函数中略微干扰它们的相对权重？
So, we -- the question is, uh, how, um,
所以，我们 - 问题是，呃，怎么样，嗯，
sensitive were the tasks if we were to,
敏感是我们的任务，
um, add weights to the different tasks?
嗯，为不同的任务增加权重？
We [NOISE] did in the optimization kind of did a lot of trickery on
我们[NOISE]在优化方面做了很多诡计
how to train it but we never said this task only matters like 0,5 or something.
如何训练它，但我们从来没有说过这个任务只有0,5或类似的事情。
So, we didn't do that analysis. Yeah?
所以，我们没有做那个分析。是吗？
Co-attention seems to be a burden a little bit.
共同关注似乎是一种负担。
In some cases, yeah.
在某些情况下，是的。
Is it the [inaudible] co-attention and order but no co-attention or is that kind of like,
是[听不清]共同关注和秩序，但没有共同关注或是那样的，
"Oh, you already saw the test data so, like, you can't use these."
“哦，你已经看过测试数据了，就像你不能使用它们一样。”
I mean, these are all dep sets.
我的意思是，这些都是dep set。
Um, but it's, you could definitely do even more architecture engineering.
嗯，但是，你绝对可以做更多的建筑工程。
In fact, there's this whole field which I don't think
事实上，我认为这是整个领域
you gotten to, right, neural architecture search?
你得到了，对，神经结构搜索？
Yeah. So like you can actually combine your reinforcement learning, um,
是啊。所以就像你实际上可以结合你的强化学习，嗯，
and you say the action space for the reinforcement learning agent
你说强化学习代理的行动空间
are trying to have a couple of
试图有两个
different modules of neural nets like maybe you want to have
可能你想要的神经网络的不同模块
like a CNN layer and then like
像CNN层然后喜欢
a memory layer and then an LSTM layer and maybe it's bidirectional and you
一个内存层，然后是一个LSTM层，也许它是双向的你
basically let a reinforcement learning agent figure out all of these decisions.
基本上让强化学习代理人弄清楚所有这些决定。
Uh, so I think it would be phenomenal to try to apply
呃，所以我认为尝试申请会是非凡的
neural architecture search not to what's
神经结构搜索不是什么
usually being done which is we already know how to do image classification,
通常做的是我们已经知道如何进行图像分类，
we'll just do it slightly better with NAS, neural architecture search.
我们只是用NAS，神经架构搜索稍微做得更好。
But we actually try to find
但我们实际上试图找到
a single architecture for multi-task learning which we don't know.
我们不知道的多任务学习的单一架构。
The problem of course is that already getting to these.
问题当然是已经到了这些问题。
All these numbers took a lot of compute time and a lot of
所有这些数字都耗费了大量的计算时间
fiddling around with stuff and it is, I can,
摆弄东西，我可以，
I can only give you sort of an idea of like how often we'd say,
我只能给你一个像我们经常说的那样的想法，
"Oh man, we got like this really amazing result
“哦，伙计，我们得到了这个非常惊人的结果
in this task but it needed this learning rate."
在这项任务中，它需要这种学习率。“
And it turns out the same model,
事实证明，同样的模型，
same set of hyperparameters everything,
一套超参数的一切，
but this other task to get to good performance needed a much higher learning rate.
但要获得良好表现的另一项任务需要更高的学习率。
And now, you try to combine those two tasks only together and you're like,
而现在，你试图将这两个任务结合在一起，你就像，
"Okay, how do you choose your learning rate now?"
“好的，你现在如何选择学习率？”
You choose the, you know,
你知道，你选择了
if you choose the task, the learning rate from the task that is, you know,
如果你选择任务，那么任务的学习率就是你知道的
bigger than the smaller tasks just doesn't work
大于小任务只是不起作用
well at all because it needed this higher learning rate.
好吧，因为它需要更高的学习率。
If you'd use the higher learning rate that the smaller task and the smaller dataset,
如果您使用较小任务和较小数据集的较高学习率，
uh, did really well on then the large one just overfits and doesn't work well either.
呃，当时的确很好，那个大的只是套装，也不好用。
If you try to do the average, neither of the two work.
如果你试图做到平均水平，两者都不起作用。
Like there's a lot of complexity in trying to do multitask learning.
就像在尝试进行多任务学习时有很多复杂性。
That's why, that's why it's such an interesting I think, uh, research challenge.
这就是为什么，这就是为什么我认为这是一个有趣的研究挑战。
All right, any more questions about this first set of results?
好的，还有关于第一组结果的问题吗？
They get, they will get better.
他们得到了，他们会变得更好。
We, we have, we have had some ideas already,
我们已经有了一些想法，
uh, on, on how to improve them.
呃，关于如何改进它们。
All right. So, uh,
行。所以，呃，
how did we actually train this whole thing?
我们怎么实际训练这整件事？
Um, we had tried a lot of different things but in the end, uh,
嗯，我们尝试了很多不同的东西，但最后，呃，
this very simple fully joint training strategy actually worked the best.
这个非常简单的全联合培训策略实际上是最好的。
Uh, and that is you basically take a mini batch from each of
呃，那就是你基本上从每个人那里拿一个小批量
the different tasks and you just train on that mini batch from that task.
不同的任务，你只需要从那个任务上训练那个迷你批次。
So basically just going through all the 10 tasks and then round robin,
所以基本上只需要完成所有10个任务然后循环，
uh, go through them.
呃，通过他们。
Um, now it turns out, ah,
嗯，现在结果啊，
that that does not work,
那不起作用，
uh, quite as well, uh,
呃，好吧，呃，
as another training strategy and if you look into optimization,
作为另一种培训策略，如果你研究优化，
uh, strategies in neural nets, uh,
呃，神经网络的策略，呃，
there are actually a couple of papers on
实际上有几篇论文
so-called curriculum learning, where the idea is,
所谓的课程学习，其理念是，
you start with training your model with simple pro- simple instances of your problems.
您首先要通过简单的问题简单实例来训练您的模型。
So, in translation, for instance you start training with
所以，在翻译中，例如你开始训练
very short sentences and then you go to larger and larger,
非常短的句子，然后你去越来越大，
uh, sentences, uh, or longer and longer sentences.
呃，句子，呃，或者更长，更长的句子。
Uh, now it turns out for multi-task learning,
呃，现在结果是多任务学习，
you actually want to do the opposite.
你真的想要做相反的事情。
You wanna do anti-curriculum learning.
你想做反课程学习。
Uh, and that is you start with the hardest tasks and you iterate on
呃，那就是你从最困难的任务开始，然后你继续
those for a while and then you add the simple tasks later on.
那些有一段时间，然后你稍后添加简单的任务。
And to some degree, I think this is intuitive because when
在某种程度上，我认为这很直观，因为什么时候
you train this very gigantic and powerful model,
你训练这个非常强大的模型，
uh, on a very simple task like
呃，在一个非常简单的任务上
sentiment and you just need to classify everything to be positive or negative.
情绪，你只需要将一切都归类为正面或负面。
You train all of these weights and you arrive at sort of, uh,
你训练所有这些重量，你到达那种，呃，
local optima that are quite deep and very
局部最佳，非常深刻和非常
specific to just generating these two words and if you then try to get out of that,
特定于生成这两个单词，如果你然后试图摆脱它，
out of this local optimum for that very simple task
超出这个非常简单的任务的局部最优
and then try to generate all these other kinds of words and point to different,
然后尝试生成所有这些其他类型的单词并指向不同的，
you know, words it's never seen before then SQuAD,
你知道吗，那之前从未见过的SQUAD，
it's very very hard to come out of that local optimum.
从当地的最佳状态中走出来是非常困难的。
And that is sort of my intuition of why it actually makes more sense to say,
这就是我对为什么说实际上更有意义的直觉，
"Let's start with SQuAD and machine translation and a couple of these harder tasks.
“让我们从SQuAD和机器翻译开始，以及其中一些更难的任务。
We'll make the model very general purpose.
我们将使模型非常通用。
It has to generate a lot of different things,
它必须产生许多不同的东西，
create a softmax, German words,
创建一个softmax，德语单词，
it has to point to all kinds of
它必须指向各种各样的
different words and be able to parse all kinds of different Wikipedia paragraphs."
不同的单词，能够解析各种不同的维基百科段落。“
And you do that a couple of times and then once you've finished,
你这样做了几次然后一旦你完成，
uh, this sort of pre-training, uh,
呃，这种预训练，呃，
stage or anti-curriculum, then you move on and add sort of the simpler smaller tasks.
阶段或反课程，然后你继续前进并添加更简单的小任务。
So [NOISE] with that, uh,
所以[NOISE]，呃，
relatively simple change that did take us,
相对简单的改变确实带走了我们，
uh, a lot of different experiments to get to.
呃，有很多不同的实验要做。
Um, we actually, uh,
嗯，我们其实，呃，
closed or, uh, um,
关闭，呃，嗯，
went closer to closing that gap and now, um,
接近缩小差距，现在，嗯，
we're only sort of, um, 14, uh, away.
我们只是那种，嗯，14，呃，离开。
Right, yeah, uh, 14 or so.
对，是的，呃，14岁左右。
Uh, but there's still, uh,
呃，但是还有，呃，
a big gap and the biggest, uh,
差距很大，最大，呃，
nuisance and issue that we had was with a translation.
我们遇到的滋扰和问题是翻译。
Basically, if you look at all of these,
基本上，如果你看看所有这些，
most things are kind of similar,
大多数事情都有点类似，
get slightly better, um and it's sort of a toss up but then and,
得到稍微好一点，嗯，这有点折腾但是然后，
and roughly similar, but translation was really bad.
和大致相似，但翻译真的很糟糕。
It's almost only half, uh,
它几乎只有一半，呃，
the performance in the multitask learning setup,
多任务学习设置中的性能，
and part of that is because translation was the only task that had
部分原因是因为翻译是唯一的任务
a very large Softmax vocabulary of words that were in no other task.
一个非常大的Softmax词汇词汇，没有任何其他任务。
And most of the other tasks,
而且大多数其他任务，
actually were doing really well with pointing.
实际上指点真的很好。
And so, uh, my interpretation of this was that the intermediate layers,
所以，呃，我对此的解释是中间层，
all these representations that we learned with
我们学到的所有这些表述
bi-directional LSTMs and transformers, they got really,
双向LSTM和变压器，他们真的，
really good at being pointed to,
非常善于被指出，
like creating hidden representations that the answer module can point to very accurately.
比如创建应答模块可以非常准确地指出的隐藏表示。
And then you have this one task that is like,
然后你有这个任务，就像，
I don't point to almost anything,
我几乎没有指出什么，
I basically just generate other words and then different vocabulary.
我基本上只生成其他单词然后生成不同的词汇。
And so those hidden representations became less useful for that task.
因此，这些隐藏的表示对于该任务变得不那么有用。
And so, that was one of the insights and that led
所以，这是其中一个洞察力和领导力
to one of the ways of trying to improve this.
试图改善这一点的方法之一。
Now, one of the interesting issues that we had is,
现在，我们遇到的一个有趣的问题是，
when we improved the model,
当我们改进模型时，
the multi-single model for all 10 tasks,
所有10个任务的多单模型，
a lot of times we said, well,
很多次我们说，好吧，
but now we also have to go back and run
但现在我们还要回去跑步
10 more experiments on all the single tasks to have a proper comparison, right?
在所有单个任务上进行10次实验以进行适当的比较，对吧？
Because if you tune the thing you care about,
因为如果你调整你关心的东西，
and you stop tuning the thing you wanna show you can do better than,
而你停止调整你想表明你可以做得更好的事情，
then that's not fair.
那不公平。
Uh, so you always wanna give as much, uh,
呃，所以你总是想给予多少，呃，
TLC and focus and experiment time to your baselines.
TLC以及对基准的关注和实验时间。
And so, uh, in some cases we actually,
所以，呃，在某些情况下我们实际上，
uh, improved some- improved something.
呃，改进了一些改进的东西。
But then, we improve both the 10 separate models and our model,
但是，我们改进了10个单独的模型和我们的模型，
and some cases like the 10 separate models improved, even more.
有些案例比如10个单独的模型改进了，甚至更多。
So the gap got even larger.
所以差距变得更大了。
It's kind of the opposite of what we wanted to show, but in general,
这与我们想要表现的相反，但总的来说，
it's better for both tests,
这两个测试都比较好
uh, for the architecture overall.
呃，对整个建筑而言。
So basically, we started, uh,
基本上，我们开始了，呃，
with this fully joint training and we have
通过这种全面的联合培训，我们有
this sort of set of single models that we could,
这种单一模型我们可以，
in theory with some oracle,
理论上与某些神谕，
kind of just sum up, uh,
总结一下，呃，
in their scores, to get a decaScore.
在他们的分数，得到decaScore。
So the gap started at 23.
所以差距从23开始。
And then, uh, we basically did this anti-curriculum training,
然后，呃，我们基本上做了这个反课程培训，
uh, which, uh, lowered the gap to 15.
呃，呃，把差距缩小到15。
So we're kind of excited,
所以我们很兴奋，
uh, making good progress.
呃，取得了很好的进展。
Then we switched, uh,
然后我们换了，呃，
from GloVe and use CoVe.
来自GloVe并使用CoVe。
So contextual vectors, um,
所以语境向量，嗯，
which actually increased the gap a lot again.
这实际上又增加了很多差距。
So everything got better, but the 10 separate models got
所以一切都变得更好，但10个独立的模型得到了
even better than the one single model that does the 10 tasks.
甚至比执行10项任务的单一模型更好。
Um, so the gap got bigger,
嗯，差距越大，
but everybody's performance increased.
但每个人的表现都有所增加。
So it was still overall a good thing.
所以这仍然是一件好事。
Uh, and then, uh, we basically figured,
呃，然后，呃，我们基本上认为，
especially with this machine translation issue,
特别是这个机器翻译问题，
we shouldn't just pre-train on SQuAD,
我们不应该只对SQuAD进行预训练，
but we also should include machine translation in
但我们也应该包括机器翻译
this pre-training in the beginning so the model doesn't just start learning to point.
这个预训练在开始时所以模型不仅仅是开始学习点。
Um, and that helped us, uh,
嗯，这对我们有帮助，呃，
to reduce the gap between the 10 separate models,
减少10个独立模型之间的差距，
Oracle, and the single model to about five points.
甲骨文和单一模式大约五点。
And then, uh, we basically said,
然后，呃，我们基本上说，
okay, translation is still not that good.
好吧，翻译还不是那么好。
We just keep oversampling.
我们只是保持过采样。
So, every time we go through one of these round robin mini-batch sets,
所以，每次我们通过其中一个循环小批量套装，
we just always include machine translation.
我们总是包括机器翻译。
And that basically allowed us to then reduce the gap,
这基本上允许我们缩小差距，
uh, to just a single point.
呃，只是一点。
So now, uh, we started, uh,
所以现在，呃，我们开始了，呃，
couple of, several months ago, uh, at 586.
几个月前的几个，呃，586。
And now the single, uh,
现在单身，呃，
oracle with 10 different models,
oracle有10种不同型号，
if you were to sum them up,
如果你要总结一下，
get 618, uh, and the, you know,
得到618，呃，你知道，
better contextual vectors and tuning and adding a lot more translation,
更好的上下文向量和调整，并添加更多的翻译，
and translation is still not as good as we would like it to be, uh,
翻译仍然不如我们希望的那样好，呃，
but now, several of the other tasks benefited a bunch.
但现在，其他一些任务受益匪浅。
And now we're basically one decaScore away from
而现在我们基本上只有一个十分之一的分数
having a single model that does as well as 10 different ones.
拥有一个与10个不同模型一样的模型。
And you can basically,
你基本上可以，
you could run even more experiments,
你可以运行更多的实验，
in some ways you could burn millions of dollars on AWS cost here,
在某些方面，你可以在这里花费数百万美元的AWS成本，
because most of the time we kept the hyperparameters of these different models the same.
因为大多数时候我们保持这些不同模型的超参数相同。
Like each of these, you could also say, well,
像这些中的每一个，你也可以说，嗯，
maybe this multitask model needs to have 50 more layers,
也许这个多任务模型需要多50个层，
or maybe 19 more layers,
或者更多19层，
or maybe five more layers and maybe they should be 1000,
或者可能还有五层，也许它们应该是1000，
you know, wider in their hidden dimensions.
你知道，隐藏的维度更广。
And you could basically run a lot more experiments.
你基本上可以进行更多的实验。
Maybe hopefully, eventually, the community jointly does that,
也许希望最终，社区共同做到这一点，
and then we can kind of move, move towards that.
然后我们可以采取行动，朝着这一目标迈进。
But we figured, okay, we're pretty close,
但我们想，好吧，我们非常接近，
so we moved on to some other things which maybe I'll tell you about next year.
所以我们转到了其他一些我可能会在明年告诉你的事情。
[LAUGHTER] But basically, um,
[大笑]但基本上，嗯，
let's do some analysis of what happened in this project.
让我们对这个项目中发生的事情做一些分析。
And this is kind of, I think something that I would encourage you all to do as well.
这有点像，我想我会鼓励你们所做的一切。
Like you, you can chase the numbers for a while and in some ways,
和你一样，你可以追逐一段时间的数字，在某些方面，
you should always be skeptical about your evaluations.
你应该总是对你的评价持怀疑态度。
And in some cases,
在某些情况下，
you've seen- we've seen in the NLP community people
你见过 - 我们在NLP社区看过人们
like basically just optimize BLEU scores for translation for years.
就像基本上只是优化BLEU分数翻译多年。
And then somebody came out with a paper and said, well,
然后有人拿出一张纸说，好吧，
it turns out BLEU metrics and human evaluations on how good of a translation is this,
事实证明BLEU指标和人工评估翻译的好坏程度，
aren't actually that correlated.
实际上并不相关。
And you're like, ah, that that sucks,
而你就是啊，那太糟糕了，
we just spent years of our lives tuning that metric and publishing a bunch of papers.
我们只是花了很多年的时间来调整这个指标并发表了大量的论文。
Um, and so in some ways all of these metrics have flaws, uh, you know,
嗯，所以在某些方面所有这些指标都有缺陷，呃，你知道，
root scores summarization is a super,
root分数摘要是超级的，
uh, subjective kind of a task.
呃，主观的一种任务。
And summarization, for instance,
例如，总结
when you analyze the errors, uh,
当你分析错误时，呃，
you often realize that word vectors have problems too.
你经常意识到单词向量也存在问题。
So, for instance, the word vector for Jason, John,
所以，例如，杰森，约翰，矢量这个词，
and Jeremy are all kind of the same, right?
和杰里米都是一样的，对吧？
They all have similar, uh,
他们都有相似的，呃，
distributions, similar contexts, windows, and so on.
分布，类似的上下文，窗口等。
And so word vectors of names are very similar.
所以名字的单词向量非常相似。
And so in summarization errors, you realize, oh,
所以在摘要错误中，你会发现，哦，
well, you know, this article, news article talked about Jeremy being kidnapped.
好吧，你知道，这篇新闻文章谈到了杰里米被绑架。
But the summary said that Jason was kidnapped.
但总结说杰森被绑架了。
And you like, well, you know, in the evaluation metric
而且，您知道，在评估指标中
that's just one word is off and like, all the rest is correct,
只有一个词是关闭的，所有其余的都是正确的，
but it's a pretty important word.
但这是一个非常重要的词。
And so, word vectors have like issues
因此，单词向量有类似的问题
for summarization that are pretty fundamental and I don't think,
总结是非常基本的，我不认为，
uh, anybody's tackling really well right now.
呃，现在任何人都很好地解决了问题。
Uh, and so all of these metrics have issues.
呃，所有这些指标都存在问题。
I would argue though that combining the 10 actually
我认为虽然实际上结合了10个
makes it less problematic and more meaningful,
使问题更少，更有意义，
than looking at each one separately.
而不是分别看每一个。
Uh, because now you can't use the idiosyncrasies of
呃，因为现在你不能使用它的特质了
one particular evaluation metric to just get like your score a little bit higher.
一个特定的评估指标，让你的得分更高一些。
Um, because then, if you just tune with that particular thing in mind,
嗯，因为那样，如果你只是考虑到那个特定的东西，
it will hurt some of the other tasks and you won't get to the sort of general,
它会伤害其他一些任务，你不会达到那种一般性，
uh, NLP model that much more easily.
呃，NLP模型更容易。
All right. So now, let's do some analysis uh,
行。那么现在，让我们做一些分析呃，
of this model and, uh,
这个模型，呃，
look at, and this is the kinda thing that comes to one of the questions that was asked.
看看，这是有问题的其中一个问题。
Uh, is this model able to kind of generate the right words for the right tasks?
呃，这个模型能够为正确的任务生成正确的单词吗？
And here, we basically looked at the distributions of how often, uh,
在这里，我们基本上看了多久的分布，呃，
the model generated words in these differen- with these three different mechanisms,
模型在这些不同的机制中产生了这些不同的机制，
Softmax vocabulary, context pointers, or question pointers.
Softmax词汇表，上下文指针或问题指针。
And, uh, as you can see,
而且，呃，正如你所看到的，
in the majority of cases it knows exactly how to generate.
在大多数情况下，它确切知道如何生成。
So, uh, for, uh,
所以，呃，因为，呃，
question, answering, and semantic role labeling,
问题，回答和语义角色标签，
and SQuAD and Wiki SQL and,
和SQuAD和Wiki SQL以及
um, summarization, it basically uses the context pointer.
嗯，摘要，它基本上使用了上下文指针。
So it just points into the context document.
所以它只是指向上下文文档。
And we know for SQuAD,
我们知道SQUAD，
that is basically [NOISE] how the data set was generated.
这基本上是[NOISE]如何生成数据集。
So that's the only thing that that really makes a lot of sense.
所以这是唯一真正有意义的东西。
Uh, what's kind of cool is that in some cases like summarization,
呃，有点酷，在某些情况下，如摘要，
it sometimes creates new words or, you know,
它有时会创造新词，或者，你知道，
that weren't in the context document wherein pointed to.
那些不在指向的上下文文档中。
Uh, and for zero-shot relation extraction,
呃，对于零射击关系提取，
also sometimes uses, uh,
也有时使用，呃，
this external vocabulary and in some cases the context pointer.
这个外部词汇表，在某些情况下还有上下文指针。
So for the most part, uh,
所以在大多数情况下，呃，
this model doesn't- is not confused how to execute on a task given, uh,
这个模型不会混淆如何执行给定的任务，呃，
this question formalism rather than, uh, the,
这个问题形式主义而不是呃，
uh, format of sort of this is the task,
呃，这种格式是任务，
just do this particular test.
只做这个特别的测试。
Now, um, you might argue,
嗯，你可能会说，
okay, I'm not that impressed by, you know,
好吧，我不是那么留下深刻印象，你知道，
having the performance be slightly the same with one model versus
具有与一个型号相比的性能略有相同
10 separate models even though it's nice if you wanna deploy it right,
10个独立的模型，即使你想要正确部署也很好，
like, uses less RAM and all of that,
比如，使用更少的RAM和所有这些，
assuming they're the same size,
假设它们的大小相同，
uh, while, you know, one-tenth the size.
呃，虽然，你知道，只有十分之一。
But what I'm excited about is more like the next couple of results.
但令我兴奋的是更接近下一对结果。
And namely, sort of this transfer learning,
就是说，这种转移学习，
domain adaptation, and zero-shot,
域适应和零射击，
uh, these kinds of capabilities.
呃，这些能力。
So here, uh, we chose two data sets that weren't included in the original 10.
所以在这里，呃，我们选择了原始10中未包含的两个数据集。
And we basically trained a pre-trained model on this versus a random model.
我们基本上训练了一个预训练的模型与随机模型。
And, uh, randomly here again,
而且，呃，再次在这里，
they're the same architecture,
他们是相同的架构，
and pre-trained means the entirety of the model was pre-trained.
预训练意味着整个模型都经过预先训练。
All the, you know,
所有，你知道，
encoders including the decoder in the Softmax and everything, uh,
编码器包括Softmax中的解码器和一切，呃，
and to two other tasks where another IWSLT language pair namely,
以及另外两个IWSLT语言对的其他任务，
translating from English to Czech, uh,
从英语翻译成捷克语，呃，
and named entity recognition tasks that you all know very well.
和你们都非常了解的命名实体识别任务。
So basically what we found is that,
基本上我们发现的是，
uh, it converges much more quickly,
呃，它收敛得更快，
uh, in the beginning, uh, and then,
呃，一开始，呃，然后，
there's still a significant but not gigantic gap.
还有一个重要但不是巨大的差距。
So this pre-training on these completely separate kinds of task had helped.
因此，对这些完全独立的任务进行预训练有所帮助。
And, uh, I think that's,
而且，呃，我想是的，
that's pretty exciting, um,
那非常令人兴奋，嗯，
especially sort of the quicker convergence, like,
特别是更快的收敛，如，
learning more quickly, uh,
学得更快，呃，
whatever new task you, you come up with,
无论你做什么新任务，你想出来，
which also means in some cases you can get away with
这也意味着在某些情况下你可以逃脱
less training data on these new- on these new tasks.
关于这些新任务的培训数据较少。
Uh, now domain adaptation is kind of the simpler form of transfer learning,
呃，现在域名改编是一种更简单的转学方式，
where you basically just have a different,
你基本上只是有一个不同的，
uh, type of, uh,
呃，类型，呃，
you know, distribution for your words.
你知道，分发你的话。
Uh, we mentioned we have the Stanford Sentiment Treebank for sentiment analysis.
呃，我们提到我们有斯坦福情绪树库进行情绪分析。
Uh, and then we analyze this on different,
呃，然后我们分析不同的，
uh, sentiment data sets,
呃，情绪数据集，
namely Amazon product reviews and Yelp restaurant reviews,
即亚马逊产品评论和Yelp餐厅评论，
and out of the box without any training,
开箱即用，未经任何培训，
the model just got 80% accuracy on both of those data sets.
该模型在这两个数据集上都获得了80％的准确率。
Uh, and I think for practitioners,
呃，我认为对于从业者来说，
that is pretty exciting because you basically didn't have to train anything,
这非常令人兴奋，因为你基本上不需要训练任何东西，
it just kind of worked out of the box,
它只是一种开箱即用的方式，
download it from GitHub, and run it.
从GitHub下载并运行它。
Uh, SNLI, that was slightly different.
呃，SNLI，略有不同。
It didn't quite work as well.
它并没有那么好用。
It's another natural language inference data set,
这是另一种自然语言推理数据集，
but has very different- a very different distribution, different, uh,
但是有很大的不同 - 一个非常不同的分布，不同，呃，
kinds of domains, uh, that,
各种领域，呃，那，
uh, these entailment questions are asked over.
呃，这些蕴涵问题都被问到了。
Uh, and here, out of the box it achieved 62.
呃，在这里，开箱即可达到62。
Uh, but then, uh, once you fine tuned it and
呃，但是，呃，一旦你对它进行了很好的调整
similar to these experiments here continue to actually train on this data set,
类似于这些实验，这里继续实际训练这个数据集，
it quickly uh, converged to 87 which was
很快，呃，收敛到了87
still two percent gain over a randomlyor initialized McCann model. Yeah.
与随机或初始化的McCann模型相比仍有2％的收益。是啊。
In that experiment, did you evaluate how much less data you can get away with?
在那个实验中，您是否评估了可以获得的数据少得多？
Did we evaluate how much less data we can get away with? We didn't.
我们是否评估了我们可以获得的数据少得多？我们没有。
And in some ways, whenever you would run this experiment,
在某些方面，每当你运行这个实验，
you'd basically be like, you'd still not do as well.
你基本上就是这样，你仍然没有做得那么好。
Like, everything- all these models will still do better with more training data.
就像，一切 - 所有这些模型仍然可以用更多的训练数据做得更好。
So you just kind of, it would be a fuzzy kind of say,
所以你只是那种，这将是一种模糊的说法，
like, cut- fuzzy sort of result, right?
比如，削减模糊的结果吧？
Where you say, well, with one-tenth we might get
你说的地方，我们可能会得到十分之一
to 50 and the other model might get only to 40,
到50，而另一个模型可能只有40，
doing something like that.
做那样的事情。
Um, we don't- I don't have those numbers.
嗯，我们不 - 我没有这些数字。
It would be kind of actually also a neat, neat, uh,
它实际上也是一种整洁，整洁，呃，
analysis to do. Yeah.
做分析。是啊。
So if you wanted to like train on a new task [inaudible].
所以如果你想在新任务上训练[音频不清晰]。
Yeah.
是啊。
[inaudible] .
[听不清]。
So, do we have the code to train a new task? Yes, we do.
那么，我们是否有代码来训练一项新任务？是的，我们这样做。
Um, you can just, uh, edit,
嗯，你可以，呃，编辑，
make it into this format using context.
使用上下文使其成为这种格式。
Here's a question, simple like CSV type format,
这是一个简单的问题，比如CSV格式，
and then you add it and you can both like train the pre-trained model yourself.
然后你添加它，你们都可以自己训练预训练的模型。
You can download a pre-trained model and just add it. So I'll look it up, yeah.
您可以下载预先训练的模型并添加它。所以我会查一查，是的。
Do you know how this compares to using other kinds of pre-trained representations like, say BERT?
您是否知道如何使用其他类型的预训练表示，例如BERT？
So, um, it's a great question.
所以，嗯，这是一个很好的问题。
So how does this compare to other pre-trained representations like BERT?
那么这与BERT等其他预先训练的表现相比如何？
So, in some ways,
所以，在某些方面，
people say BERT is kind of this model that does everything,
人们说BERT就是这种做所有事情的模型，
but when you actually read the paper, you realize, well,
但是当你真正阅读这篇论文时，你会意识到，
it's a separate model for these different tasks, right?
它是这些不同任务的独立模型，对吧？
If you wanted to have a classification task,
如果您想要分类任务，
you have a little token in the beginning,
你在开始时有一点标记，
and you have a different top layer.
你有一个不同的顶层。
If you wanna do a sequence labeling task,
如果你想做一个序列标签任务，
you have a different top layer.
你有一个不同的顶层。
If you wanted to do a sequence extraction task,
如果你想做一个序列提取任务，
you have a different top layer.
你有一个不同的顶层。
So, BERT isn't actually a single model for all of these different tasks.
因此，BERT实际上并不是所有这些不同任务的单一模型。
Ah, and then, on all the results,
啊，然后，在所有的结果，
there's a lot of extra tuning for each of the data sets,
每个数据集都有很多额外的调整，
and tasks, uh, that, you know,
和任务，呃，你知道，
different learning rate for this task, uh,
这项任务的学习率不同，呃，
different size, or different sets of BERT, and so on.
不同大小，或不同的BERT集等。
So, we're also super excited, we're like maybe this is it,
所以，我们也非常兴奋，我们也许就是这样，
we'll just run everything on BERT,
我们只需在BERT上运行一切，
and then we looked into all the details,
然后我们调查了所有的细节，
and there's so much excitement in the beginning.
一开始就有这么多的兴奋。
And then the more we dug through the details,
然后我们越是挖掘细节，
the less excited we became as this being like sort of the answer,
我们变得越不兴奋，因为这就像答案一样，
because it is not a single model.
因为它不是单一的模型。
Uh, in some ways, it's probably better to- for pre-training.
呃，在某些方面，对于预训练来说可能更好。
So instead of CoVe,
而不是CoVe，
you can have kind of BERT at the very beginning,
你可以在一开始就有一种BERT，
and my hunch is everything will get slightly better,
我的预感是一切都会变得更好，
but you still need to have, um,
但你仍然需要，嗯，
a lot of the- a lot of the other sort of modeling architecture on top of it.
很多其他类型的建模体系结构。
Uh, and then the sad thing is to really get the state of the art results,
呃，然后可悲的是要真正获得最先进的结果，
there's a lot of very spec- task-specific tuning of those last top layers.
这些最后的顶层有很多特定于特定任务的调整。
So, if you try to unify that task-specific tuning,
因此，如果您尝试统一特定于任务的调整，
you lose a lot of the good performance of BERT.
你失去了很多BERT的优秀表现。
Um, so, unfortunately, it's not quite the sort of,
嗯，不幸的是，它不是那种，
"Oh, just use BERT for it,
“哦，只需使用BERT，
and you'll just have state-of-the-art numbers and all the things."
而且你将拥有最先进的数字和所有的东西。“
Um, I could probably go like talk about it a lot more, but, uh,
嗯，我可能会更喜欢谈论它，但是，呃，
I think it still makes sense to think about, um,
我觉得考虑一下还是有意义的，嗯，
some of the ideas from BERT,
BERT的一些想法，
like basically, add as one of the tasks language modeling.
像基本上一样，添加为语言建模任务之一。
That would be very likely the task  that helps the most for all the other tasks,
这很可能是帮助所有其他任务最多的任务，
and we should include that, uh,
我们应该包括那个，呃，
it also would be nice to have a faster model right now.
现在拥有一个更快的模型也会很高兴。
Um, it's hard to do language modeling is very, very large,
嗯，语言建模很难，非常非常大，
it benefits even more from,
它从中获益更多
you know, billions and billions of words.
你知道，数十亿和数十亿字。
It's hard to train the McCann model,
训练McCann模型很难，
this current question answering model of the co-attention mechanism of the question
这个问题的共同关注机制的当前问题回答模型
with like an increasingly large context.
与越来越大的背景。
So you'd have to kind of split it also like BERT,
所以你必须把它分开，就像BERT一样
works also reasonably well only for like at most I think 500 words or so,
工作也相当不错只是为了最多我认为500字左右，
and if you wanted to do summarization you'd basically have to cut
如果你想做总结，你基本上必须削减
the original document to only 500 words, and then try to summarize it.
原始文件只有500字，然后尝试总结一下。
So, there are a lot of like devil in the details that they didn't have to figure out,
所以，细节中有很多像魔鬼一样，他们没有弄清楚，
because they said, "Well, we'll just sort of just like word vectors,
因为他们说，“好吧，我们就像文字向量一样，
we can take them in, and then we do a lot of other stuff that is task-specific,
我们可以接受他们，然后我们做了很多其他任务，特定于任务，
um, with those- those word vectors,
嗯，那些 - 那些单词向量，
or with the BERT architecture."
或者采用BERT架构。“
I still- I don't want to- this BERT is obviously amazing,
我仍然 - 我不想 - 这个BERT显然是惊人的，
and we are looking into trying to use ideas from it.
我们正在考虑尝试使用它的想法。
But unfortunately, it wasn't just sort of a silver bullet to
但不幸的是，它不仅仅是一颗银弹
solve multi-task learning. Mm-hmm?
解决多任务学习问题。 MM-嗯？
Pre-training process to be considered, uh,
培训前的过程需要考虑，呃，
prioritized sampling based off of how much fewer group, how much loss there is?
优先抽样基于多少少组，有多少损失？
Sorry, did we- say again?
对不起，我们再说一次吗？
Would you consider prioritizing sampling [inaudible]?
您会考虑优先采样[听不清]吗？
So, did we consider prioritizing the sampling?
那么，我们是否考虑优先考虑抽样？
So in some ways with this pre-trained strategy here, um,
所以在这里采用这种预先训练的策略，嗯，
that's kind of what we did by basically focusing on these really hard tasks.
这就是我们基本上专注于这些非常艰巨的任务所做的事情。
And, uh, a lot of like the gap in the end was improved by really waiting for,
而且，呃，很多像最后的差距通过真正的等待改善了，
like four of the tasks at the very end,
像最后的四个任务，
uh, bef- unti- you know, uh,
呃，bef- unti-你知道吗，呃，
until after you're gone through, uh,
直到你经历过，呃，
sort of oversampling all of these,
对所有这些进行过采样，
uh, really hard tasks.
呃，真的很难完成任务。
In the last 10 minutes, uh, basically, uh,
在最后10分钟，呃，基本上，呃，
th- the most exciting thing, uh,
最令人兴奋的事，呃，
for- for last though I think you could also do a lot more work in this direction.
因为最后我认为你也可以在这方面做更多的工作。
Uh, I mentioned the sole question pointer
呃，我提到了唯一的问题指针
and zero short learning in the beginning, and, uh,
一开始就没有短暂的学习，呃，
we basically just tried to play around with that a little bit, um,
我们基本上只是想尝试一下，嗯，
and found that in some cases,
并发现在某些情况下，
it actually kind of magically works.
它实际上有点神奇。
Uh, so here, we tried, uh,
呃，所以在这里，我们试过，呃，
a sentence John had a party,
约翰参加一个派对，
but no one came, and he was all alone.
但没有人来，他一个人。
And then we asked, "Is this story sad, or happy?"
然后我们问道：“这个故事难过，还是开心？”
And while the model could've, you know,
虽然模型可以，但你知道，
generate some random German words,
生成一些随机的德语单词，
or some random SQL words,
或者一些随机的SQL词，
or it's just said whatever,
或者只是说什么，
it actually pointed to, of all the words,
它实际上指出了所有的话，
you could've pointed to in the context or the question that
你可以在上下文或问题中指出
pointed to "Sad", which is pretty cool.
指着“悲伤”，这很酷。
Like- and it's just one small sample,
喜欢 - 它只是一个小样本，
and, you know, you could do a lot more,
而且，你知道，你可以做更多，
you could try to come up with a very large zero-shot kind of classification data set,
你可以试着想出一个非常大的零镜头分类数据集，
which is actually kind of hard too.
这实际上也很难。
You have to be quite creative, it's not like you can just say, "Oh,
你必须非常有创意，这不像你只能说，“哦，
it would just take all these reviews,
它会采取所有这些评论，
and label them as these, you know, positive negative.
并将它们标记为这些，你知道，正面否定。
Ah, but so, I think we- we need to do more work in that direction.
啊，但是，我认为我们 - 我们需要在这方面做更多的工作。
Somebody will hopefully create a zero-shot kind of task data set,
有人希望创建一个零镜头的任务数据集，
that is not just zero-shot for, you know,
这不仅仅是零射击，你知道，
kind of new distributions or something with completely different, uh, outputs.
一种新的发行版或具有完全不同的呃输出的东西。
Uh, but we- we tried a couple,
呃，但是我们 - 我们尝了几个，
and it doesn't always work, right.
它并不总是有效，对吧。
You can be adversarial about it,
你可以对抗它，
you can make this basically looks most similar to,
你可以使这看起来基本上看起来最相似，
is the sentiment positive or negative?
情绪是积极的还是消极的？
Uh, is this sen- is this sentence positive or negative?
呃，这句话是正面还是负面？
That was the formalism we had for sentiment analysis.
这就是我们对情绪分析的形式主义。
And so you could,
所以你可以，
if you make the question more and more different,
如果你提出的问题越来越不同，
eventually, it'll kinda get tripped up.
最终，它会被绊倒。
Ah, and it's clear that it's benefited, uh,
啊，很明显它受益了，呃，
from the word vectors,
从单词向量，
of sad being closer to negative,
悲伤接近消极，
and then understanding sort of through all these,
然后了解所有这些，
uh, correlations, and- and, uh,
呃，相关性，和 - 呃，
deep representations that there are other sort of sad words in this context,
深刻的表示在这种情况下还有其他类型的悲伤词，
or- or whatever it is.
或 - 或者不管它是什么。
Uh, and so, it was able to point to this.
呃，等等，它能够指出这一点。
But you can be adversarial, it doesn't always work.
但你可以是对抗性的，它并不总是有效。
But even the fact that, uh,
但即便是这样的事实，呃，
it was sort of zero-shot classification based on word vectors, uh,
它是基于单词向量的零射击分类，呃，
for new kinds of questions,
对于新的问题，
uh, personally, it was very exciting to me.
呃，就个人而言，这对我来说非常令人兴奋。
And we tried a couple of other things like,
我们尝试了其他一些事情，比如
uh, Bryan gave a talk and nobody clapped.
呃，布莱恩发表了讲话，没有人鼓掌。
Was Bryan happy, or sad?
布莱恩高兴，还是难过？
And it also got it right.
它也做对了。
So, um, there are a couple- a couple of the,
所以，嗯，还有几个 - 几个，
the examples were, were at least as happy or sad thing worked.
这些例子至少是令人高兴或悲伤的事情。
And then, uh, a couple of other sort of adjective questions that we,
然后，呃，我们还有其他一些形容词问题，
we tried but, um,
我们试过但是，嗯，
what I'm- what I would be most excited about is eventually actually
我最让我兴奋的是最终
trying to have a zero-shot classification task,
试图进行零射击分类任务，
uh, that combines the different tasks too.
呃，它也结合了不同的任务。
So, uh, unfortunately, there's no data set for that,
所以，呃，不幸的是，没有数据集，
so we didn't train it, so it doesn't happen with the model.
所以我们没有对它进行训练，因此模型不会发生这种情况。
But in theory, if you ask what is the sum- you can summarize,
但从理论上讲，如果你问什么是总和 - 你可以总结一下，
and you can translate from English into German,
你可以把英文翻译成德文，
why couldn't you ask the model for a German summary?
为什么你不能问模特德国总结？
And if that worked, eventually,
如果这有效，最终，
that would be even more amazing,
那将更加惊人，
but it, it doesn't work right now,
但是，它现在不起作用，
because we never ask it sort of for these
因为我们从来没有问过这些
compositional task- these compositional task questions.
组成任务 - 这些组成任务问题。
But is yet another interesting line of research that I think could spawn from this.
但是，我认为可以从中产生另一个有趣的研究方向。
Uh, all right.
呃，好的。
So, I hope I could show you that this sort of
所以，我希望我能告诉你这种情况
decaNLP framework is an interesting new benchmark for generalized NLP.
decaNLP框架是广义NLP的一个有趣的新基准。
Uh, I do think it's a reasonably good framework
呃，我认为这是一个相当不错的框架
for tackling a bunch of the really hard questions in the field.
解决一堆真正难以解决的问题。
Uh, more general language understanding,
呃，更一般的语言理解，
and question answering of course,
和问题回答当然，
uh, multitask learning, domain adaptation, uh,
呃，多任务学习，领域适应，呃，
which we sort of analyzed a little bit with the sentiment,
我们对这种情绪进行了一点分析，
and SNLI versus multi NLI,
和SNLI与多NLI，
um, transfer learning, and then weight sharing.
嗯，转学，然后分享体重。
I think it's clear, everybody loves weight sharing,
我觉得很明显，每个人都喜欢分享体重，
you wanna share as many weights as possible.
你想分享尽可能多的重量。
Uh, word vector started at, uh, ELMo,
呃，字矢量开始于，呃，ELMo，
CoVe, and now BERT basically share more and more,
CoVe，现在BERT基本上分享越来越多，
deeper and deeper layers.
越来越深的层次。
It would be great if we can unify that last bit also, uh,
如果我们能够统一最后一点，那将是很好的，呃，
and then share basically the entirety of the networks,
然后基本上分享整个网络，
and then eventually hopefully get to zero-shot learning.
然后最终希望得到零射击学习。
Now, there's a bunch of related work.
现在，有一堆相关的工作。
The original paper has over 100,
原始论文超过100篇，
um, citations in it, uh, of,
嗯，引用，呃，的，
of, you know, papers to other,
，你知道，给其他人的文件，
other, um, lines of, uh, work.
其他，嗯，行，呃，工作。
But, uh, this is actually zero- at least some of
但是，呃，这实际上是零 - 至少是一些
the models and papers that influenced us the most,
影响我们的模特和论文，
uh, in, in our thinking and modelling.
呃，在我们的思考和建模中。
Uh, one of them actually comes from,
呃，其中一个真的来自，
uh, the two instructors of the class.
呃，班上的两位导师。
And so, um, hopefully, uh, we can,
所以，嗯，希望，呃，我们可以，
you know, sort of think about what- what's next after all this architecture engineering.
你知道，在所有这些架构工程之后考虑下一步是什么。
And, uh, I think one potential answer to that, uh,
而且，呃，我认为一个可能的答案，呃，
is single multitask learning for more generalized NLP models.
是针对更广义的NLP模型的单一多任务学习。
[NOISE] All right. Thank you. [APPLAUSE]
[NOISE]好的。谢谢。 [掌声]